<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-10T17:32:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Our Generation</title><subtitle>This is homepage for SHS Our Generation Club.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Underneath the Blinding Lights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/star-wars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Underneath the Blinding Lights" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/star-wars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/star-wars/">&lt;p&gt;The crowd roars as the ball is jousted into the air. The cry of the stadium swings with the ball like a pendulum. At this moment, both sides of the stadium scream their war cries for blood and pain. None of them know of the blood and sweat laid underneath to fuel their dream. Qatar forced countless people to their deaths building their extravagant stadiums. According to Qatari officials, there were “between 400 and 500” deaths among workers at World Cup stadium construction sites. The workers shout for rights, help, and basic freedom all around Earth. Four hundred to five hundred construction worker deaths in Qatar while preparing for the 2022 FIFA World Cup have been widely reported and criticized. The country has faced criticism for inadequate working conditions and labor laws, with some workers facing exploitation, long hours, and hazardous working environments. According to human rights organizations, hundreds of workers have died while working on World Cup-related infrastructure projects. The Qatari government has made efforts to improve working conditions, but more needs to be done to ensure the safety and rights of all workers in the country. The international community, FIFA, and corporations with ties to World Cup projects have a responsibility to advocate for fair and safe working conditions in Qatar, as well as for all workers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Oneal Wang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oneal Wang</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">The crowd roars as the ball is jousted into the air. The cry of the stadium swings with the ball like a pendulum. At this moment, both sides of the stadium scream their war cries for blood and pain. None of them know of the blood and sweat laid underneath to fuel their dream. Qatar forced countless people to their deaths building their extravagant stadiums. According to Qatari officials, there were “between 400 and 500” deaths among workers at World Cup stadium construction sites. The workers shout for rights, help, and basic freedom all around Earth. Four hundred to five hundred construction worker deaths in Qatar while preparing for the 2022 FIFA World Cup have been widely reported and criticized. The country has faced criticism for inadequate working conditions and labor laws, with some workers facing exploitation, long hours, and hazardous working environments. According to human rights organizations, hundreds of workers have died while working on World Cup-related infrastructure projects. The Qatari government has made efforts to improve working conditions, but more needs to be done to ensure the safety and rights of all workers in the country. The international community, FIFA, and corporations with ties to World Cup projects have a responsibility to advocate for fair and safe working conditions in Qatar, as well as for all workers around the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/workersrights.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrant Workers under the Extravaganza</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrant Workers under the Extravaganza" /><published>2023-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers/">&lt;p&gt;As one of the most important sporting events in the world, the FIFA World Cup in Qatar had over 5.4 billion viewers. Since the announcement of the Qatar World Cup in December 2010, construction and preparation commenced to make the first FIFA World Cup in the Middle East possible. Immigrants from India and Africa built stadiums, secured safety of the games, and provided service, acting as a crucial factor that allowed the World Cup to take place. A total of two million migrant workers helped to facilitate the process, but among them, over 6,500 people have died due to poor living and working conditions, highlighting the underlying problem behind the World Cup and exposing the larger topic of worker abuse. The FIFA World Cup was not the first example of abuse of migrant workers as the root of the problem can be traced back to the last century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A significant factor contributing to workers’ abuse in Qatar is the Kafala System, or the Sponsorship System. Originally adopted in the 1950s, this system legally binds foreign workers to their employers, leaving the workers prone to manipulation and without the ability to escape such abuse. While the system was originally created to enhance regulation between employers and migrant workers, this policy now only takes away migrant workers’ freedom and makes them dependent on their employers. For instance, employers were responsible for renewing migrant workers’ resident permits, which the workers themselves had no control over. However, when the permits failed to be renewed, the workers then became the victims that had to bear the consequences themselves. Furthermore, the employers also had the power to cancel workers’ permits, demonstrating the power disparity which dismisses the laborer’s human rights and causes the workers to be stuck in a cycle of abuse. Furthermore, other prohibitions such as passport confiscation prevent workers from leaving the country, adding onto the problem. The lack of labor unions and labor laws in the society also shows problematic judicial and legislative practices that are hostile to migrant workers. Collectively, the system in Qatar made the migrant workers prone to labor exploitation, leaving them vulnerable during the FIFA World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the construction of the stadiums, the two largest problems the workers faced were wage delay and injustice. Amnesty International revealed that 100 employees of Qatar Meta Coats were not paid any wages for as long as seven months. In response to this, FIFA stated that they were unaware of this issue, implying that they failed to take cases of human rights abuses linked to the World Cup seriously. Moreover, even when workers were paid wages, the amount they received was extremely minimal. Ironically, while Qatar had spent nearly $220 billion on new infrastructure for the World Cup, they had kept labor costs low for the migrant workers. In addition to low wages, migrant workers in Qatar received lack of proper recognition for their deaths, and the true causes of their deaths were hidden by the responsible committees. In fact, while there have been 37 deaths that were directly linked to construction of World Cup stadiums, 34 of them were classified as “non-work related”. In many other examples, the deaths were covered up as “natural death” in order to conceal the workers’ abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding this issue, ongoing protests and public reforms were also important in dictating the prospect of migrant workers’ future. In 2017, the Qatar government signed an agreement with the International Labor Organization (ILO) to prevent labor exploitation and adhere labor practices to the international standards. This marks a sign for positive change, but it will not be effective until it is properly enforced. However, in many cases, weak implementation limits the impact of beneficial legislation to the workers. For instance, the Workers’ Welfare Standards provides restrictions on worker abuse and was meant to protect the workers under abuse, nevertheless examples of exploitation remained prevalent. Targeting the sponsorship system, the country ended the exit permit requirement in 2018 and allowed the workers to have the freedom to leave. Overall, many advancements have been made to improve the workers’ access to justice, health and safety, and wages, but in order to maintain a positive trend, there needs to be increased monitoring and detection of abuse. It is necessary for companies to respect the human rights of all workers equally for the abuse of migrant workers to one day come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;26, December. “BeIN Sports Announces Record-Breaking Cumulative Viewership of 5.4 Billion for FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022TM.” BeIN SPORTS, 26 Dec. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beinsports.com/en/fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/news/bein-sports-announces-record-breaking-cumulat/2011581&quot;&gt;https://www.beinsports.com/en/fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/news/bein-sports-announces-record-breaking-cumulat/2011581&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Profile of the FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022™​.” FIFA Publications, &lt;a href=&quot;https://publications.fifa.com/en/sustainability-report/sustainability-at-the-fifa-world-cup/profile-of-the-fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/&quot;&gt;https://publications.fifa.com/en/sustainability-report/sustainability-at-the-fifa-world-cup/profile-of-the-fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Reality Check: Migrant Workers’ Rights in Qatar.” Amnesty International, 20 Oct. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/campaigns/2019/02/reality-check-migrant-workers-rights-with-two-years-to-qatar-2022-world-cup/&quot;&gt;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/campaigns/2019/02/reality-check-migrant-workers-rights-with-two-years-to-qatar-2022-world-cup/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Revealed: 6,500 Migrant Workers Have Died in Qatar since World Cup Awarded.” The Guardian, Guardian News and Media, 23 Feb. 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/feb/23/revealed-migrant-worker-deaths-qatar-fifa-world-cup-2022&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/feb/23/revealed-migrant-worker-deaths-qatar-fifa-world-cup-2022&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Op-Ed: The Kafala Sponsorship System Fuels Modern Day Slavery.” Ed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.bu.edu/pardeeatlas/opinions/op-ed-the-kafala-sponsorship-system-fuels-modern-day-slavery/#:~:text=The%20Kafala%20sponsorship%20was%20originally,boom%20in%20these%20growing%20nations&quot;&gt;https://sites.bu.edu/pardeeatlas/opinions/op-ed-the-kafala-sponsorship-system-fuels-modern-day-slavery&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Ward, Ian. “The Many, Many Controversies Surrounding the 2022 World Cup, Explained.” Vox, Vox, 19 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/world/23450515/world-cup-fifa-qatar-2022-controversy-scandals-explained&quot;&gt;https://www.vox.com/world/23450515/world-cup-fifa-qatar-2022-controversy-scandals-explained&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Annie Zhu&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Shiksha Anand&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Annie Zhu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">As one of the most important sporting events in the world, the FIFA World Cup in Qatar had over 5.4 billion viewers. Since the announcement of the Qatar World Cup in December 2010, construction and preparation commenced to make the first FIFA World Cup in the Middle East possible. Immigrants from India and Africa built stadiums, secured safety of the games, and provided service, acting as a crucial factor that allowed the World Cup to take place. A total of two million migrant workers helped to facilitate the process, but among them, over 6,500 people have died due to poor living and working conditions, highlighting the underlying problem behind the World Cup and exposing the larger topic of worker abuse. The FIFA World Cup was not the first example of abuse of migrant workers as the root of the problem can be traced back to the last century.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/abuse.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Qatar’s Recycleble Soccer Stadium</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/qatars-recycleble/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qatar’s Recycleble Soccer Stadium" /><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/qatars-recycleble</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/qatars-recycleble/">&lt;p&gt;Stadium 974 is one of the most unique stadiums ever built, and it is important to consider its impact on sustainability when looking at the broader construction of stadiums in general. As one of the stadiums for the FIFA World Cup, Stadium 974 witnessed Korea’s loss to Brazil and elimination, Serbia failing to advance after losing 2-3 to Switzerland, and Poland narrowly making the round of 16 after a losing to the t eventual champion Argentina. As these moments are dramatic and historic in their own way, Stadium 974 is equally historic in its advancement of sustainable stadiums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stadium 974 is the first “dismountable” stadium ever built for the World Cup, and it is special for the notable use of 974 shipping containers in its construction, with their interior space being used for important functions such as bathrooms. The 974 is unique because it is the number reflecting the international dialing code of Qatar, which symbolizes a sense of welcome to other nations. It hosted seven games in the FIFA World Cup, consisting of six group stages games, and one game in the round of 16, showing its significance in the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stadium 974 is a part of Qatar’s plan to host a carbon neutral world cup, though various analyses express skepticism toward that claim. Still, Stadium 974 attempts to achieve that claim through designing and building a modular stadium that can be dismounted per-order and shipped to other locations and countries to be reassembled into a functional sports venue. This feature of reassembling addresses a specific issue that comes with constructing stadiums for major sporting events, which is when venues fall into disuse after the initial event. Such a building is also referred to as a “white elephant,” and it brings many associated environmental problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, the issue of disused stadiums has occurred in many countries. For example, the Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio De Janeiro has had very little activity after Brazil hosted the Olympic games in 2016. The Obi Stadium in South Africa that hosted FIFA World Cup matches fell into disrepair after 2010, and the Baseball stadium in Athen met a similar end after the 2004 Summer Olympics as well. These examples highlight the issue with hosting major sporting events and there are not many instances where such big stadiums are required. Therefore, when the sporting events end, people rarely use them. Furthermore, governments also willfully stop funding stadium maintenance in some cases because of the high cost, leaving the stadiums to deteriorate. This results in an environmental issue because the construction of stadiums also emits a lot of greenhouse gasses that worsen climate change. The Carbon Market Watch estimates that Qatar emitted 1.6 Megatonnes CO2 equivalent, illustrating the magnitude of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, stadium 974 theoretically solves this problem because the Qatari government can disassemble it when there are no sporting events that require this addition to the seven other stadiums. It can also be shipped to another country where an additional stadium might be needed, maximizing its convenience. This prevents the stadium from falling into disuse and stretches the utility of the carbon emission invested into the building of this stadium.
However, Qatar did not provide clear plans for the future of Stadium 974, so the true potential of Stadium 974 remains ambiguous. Further, the impact of carbon emission of Stadium 974 is not only affected by its modular design and ability to be transported, but also the distance that it is shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, although Stadium 974’s current future is ambiguous, it brings the issue of carbon emission associated with stadium construction into consideration, while also setting an example of a potential solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Irfan, Umair. “The World Cup Is Missing Its Climate Goals. It Should Still Keep Taking Shots.” Vox, Vox, 10 Dec. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/23458620/fifa-world-cup-2022-greenwashing-climate-change&quot;&gt;https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/23458620/fifa-world-cup-2022-greenwashing-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Press, Associated. “Built to Disappear: World Cup Stadium 974.” ABC Action News Tampa Bay (WFTS), ABC Action News Tampa Bay (WFTS), 3 Dec. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abcactionnews.com/sports/built-to-disappear-world-cup-stadium-974&quot;&gt;https://www.abcactionnews.com/sports/built-to-disappear-world-cup-stadium-974&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;McCarriston Feb 23, Shanna. “Look: What Abandoned Olympic Venues Look like Now, from Athens to Berlin.” CBSSports.com, 23 Feb. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbssports.com/olympics/news/look-what-abandoned-olympic-venues-look-like-now-from-athens-to-berlin/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbssports.com/olympics/news/look-what-abandoned-olympic-venues-look-like-now-from-athens-to-berlin/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Ralston, William. “No, Qatar’s World Cup Can’t Be Classed as Carbon-Neutral.” Wired, Conde Nast, 14 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/qatar-2022-world-cup-emissions/#:~:text=Despite%20efforts%20to%20reduce%20emissions,relies%20on%20questionable%20carbon%20credits&quot;&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/qatar-2022-world-cup-emissions/#:~:text=Despite%20efforts%20to%20reduce%20emissions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Dufrasne, Gilles. “Poor Tackling: Yellow Card for 2022 FIFA World Cup’s Carbon Neutrality …” Poor Tackling: Yellow Card for 2022 FIFA World Cup’s Carbon Neutrality Claim, Carbon Market Watch, 31 Oct. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbonmarketwatch.org/publications/poor-tackling-yellow-card-for-2022-fifa-world-cups-carbon-neutrality-claim&quot;&gt;https://carbonmarketwatch.org/publications/poor-tackling-yellow-card-for-2022-fifa-world-cups-carbon-neutrality-claim/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Brian Yu&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Wenyan Zhu&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Stadium 974 is one of the most unique stadiums ever built, and it is important to consider its impact on sustainability when looking at the broader construction of stadiums in general. As one of the stadiums for the FIFA World Cup, Stadium 974 witnessed Korea’s loss to Brazil and elimination, Serbia failing to advance after losing 2-3 to Switzerland, and Poland narrowly making the round of 16 after a losing to the t eventual champion Argentina. As these moments are dramatic and historic in their own way, Stadium 974 is equally historic in its advancement of sustainable stadiums.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/stadium.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Historical Figures in Workers Rights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/historical-figures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Historical Figures in Workers Rights" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/historical-figures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/historical-figures/">&lt;p&gt;During the Industrial Revolution, America transformed from an agricultural country to an industrialized one. With the emergence of large industrialists such as John D. Rockefeller with his Standard Oil company and Andrew Carnegie controlling the entire Steel industry, politicians and industrialists often neglected workers’ working conditions. Their tactic of promoting the overall economic growth has simultaneously caused serious problems such as a bigger gap of wealth and the inhumane treatment to the workers. Therefore, in response to all these intolerable regulations, workers stood up for themselves and together formed workers cooperative and labor unions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an ordinary day of 1894 in a factory in Chicago, a worker’s strike broke out in George Pullman’s railroad cars manufacturing factory. The potential causes behind the strike serve as a reminder to the public of the worsening working conditions for the lower class workers. Different from what he has always been advertising about, Pullman treated his workers badly with very minimum wage and bad working conditions (“Pullman Strike”). To make things worse, Pullman decided to cut the wage again to further exploit his employees. In reaction to this impersonal treatment, the workers in the American Railway Union (ARU) fought back. The leader of this strike was Eugene V. Debs, who was the president of ARU. He condemned Pullman’s action, and compares him to the slave owners (“The Strike of”). Debs believed that all workers should cooperate together to fight against big industrialists and for their own working conditions. Deb served six months in jail after the strike; however, this movement has brought this critical social issue to the publics’ attention. All of this led to the establishment of the Railway Labor Act of 1926 and the National Labor Relations Act of 1935, which guaranteed the workers right to join a labor union. While other people ignored workers, Debs has always been fighting against the inhumane treatment in the industries, serving as an important reformer in the workers history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Debs was imprisoned, Mary Harris Jones stood out for him and supported Pullman’s strike. Mother Jones was an Irish immigrant; after her husband and children died, she joined and supported the workers strike. She has helped African American workers to obtain their rights, held opposition to child labor, and also proposed a shorter working time. Most prominently, she has devoted to fight for the abolition of child labor. In the year of 1903, she joined a march with mill workers and child laborers from New York City to President Theodore Roosevelt’s Long Island home to advocate for their economic justice (“Mother Jones”). She once said that “today the white child is sold for two dollars a week to the manufacturer” in order to satirize the purposes of the industries for using those extremely cheap child labor. Her fierce reforms led to new child labor laws, which prevented children under 14 from working. These laws are still in place to this day to protect children from physical damage at a young age as well as their educational opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Pullman Strike.” EHISTORY, The Ohio State University, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ehistory.osu.edu/exhibitions/1912/content/pullman&quot;&gt;https://ehistory.osu.edu/exhibitions/1912/content/pullman&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“The Strike of 1894.” National Parks Service, U.S. Department of the Interior, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/pull/learn/historyculture/the-strike-of-1894.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.nps.gov/pull/learn/historyculture/the-strike-of-1894.htm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mother Jones: AFL-CIO.” AFL,
aflcio.org/about/history/labor-history-people/mother-jones.
&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Yusong Liang&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Brian Yu&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Yusong Liang</name></author><summary type="html">During the Industrial Revolution, America transformed from an agricultural country to an industrialized one. With the emergence of large industrialists such as John D. Rockefeller with his Standard Oil company and Andrew Carnegie controlling the entire Steel industry, politicians and industrialists often neglected workers’ working conditions. Their tactic of promoting the overall economic growth has simultaneously caused serious problems such as a bigger gap of wealth and the inhumane treatment to the workers. Therefore, in response to all these intolerable regulations, workers stood up for themselves and together formed workers cooperative and labor unions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/hourglass.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">America’s Immigrant Farm Workers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/america-immigrant-farm-workers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="America’s Immigrant Farm Workers" /><published>2023-02-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/america-immigrant-farm-workers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/america-immigrant-farm-workers/">&lt;p&gt;From the beginning Immigrants built America and continues to power it, making up more than a third of workers in some industries. They continue to improve our economy, creating companies around two times faster than American-born citizens. According to the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, immigrants added approximately $2 trillion to the United States’ GDP in 2016 while contributing around $458.7 billion to taxes in 2018. The National Immigration Forum reported that “employment-based immigrants are critical to the U.S. economy as they meet the temporary and permanent needs of U.S. employers in diverse industries”. The importance of immigrant workers is shown especially in terms of food production on our farms. However, despite their importance to our economy, these immigrant farm workers struggle to make ends meet as they face danger and are treated without concern for their wellbeing both on and off of the fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the USDA’s Economic Research Service, about 73% of our current agriculture workers are immigrants, driving $1.053 trillion in the farm industry and placing food on our tables for families. America’s farms are mainly located in California, Iowa, Texas, Minnesota, and Nebraska. This means that the produce that is grown in these five states are the majority of the food that ends up on America’s tables and the immigrants working on those fields keep the industry going and America fed. They face dangers everyday while working with the heavy machinery and pesticides that are used throughout the seasons. For example, in drier states such as California, wildfires are almost a constant danger and add risk for these immigrant workers on our fields. The smoke and heat of these uncontrollable flames damage the crops, and inhaling smoke and chemicals can lead to negative impacts on the workers’ physical and mental health. In 2017, wildfires in Napa and Sonoma destroyed around 500 acres of wine grapes and caused about $75 million of economic damage. Overall, immigrant workers on farms feed our families and everyday, they face danger from potential natural disasters.
On top of this, the employers of these immigrant workers often take advantage of their contracts and undermine their basic human rights. The workers struggle to feed their families, find proper housing, receive low wages, are excluded from basic workers’ rights protection laws, are unable to receive proper education, and face physical, psychological, and sexual abuse out on the fields. An immigrant worker named Patricia M. reports that one of the foremen at the farm she worked on repeatedly raped her until she became pregnant and was able to file for a lawsuit. Even after these acts of assault ended, it left her traumatized and “the rape continues to affect her”. Many of the workers are undocumented or on a guest visa, such as the H-2A visa, that allows employers to hire people from out of the country, forcing workers to live with the threat of being potentially deported constantly hanging over their heads. Also, on top of that, the wages that are provided are extremely low. A family of immigrant farm workers usually earn around $25,000 at most, even including other sources of income. This limits them in their housing options, forcing them to live in unsanitary and unsafe conditions without basic utilities and in extremely isolated areas. Furthermore, the average immigrant farmworker only receives up to an 8th grade education, and children as young as twelve years old work in the fields for around thirty hours a week. In some of the worst cases, these people who are living in extreme poverty are vulnerable to human trafficking and can be coerced into paying a ridiculously high price in exchange for being helped to cross the border. With this debt, these people are now forced to work and with the high prices of food and housing and the low wages, the cycle never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immigrant farmworkers are an essential part of the United States’ economy, making it all the more necessary that employers help them meet their necessary and basic needs. However, they often are not and even access to seemingly simple things like bathrooms and basic sanitation are hard to access. With the added precautions from COVID-19, conditions for immigrant workers continue to be devastating and add to the struggles that they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“AGRICULTURE ROBERT RIVAS.” Assembly Agriculture Committee, &lt;a href=&quot;https://agri.assembly.ca.gov/sites/agri.assembly.ca.gov/files/The%20Impact%20of%20Wildfires%20on%20California%20Agriculture%20Informational%20Hearing%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;https://agri.assembly.ca.gov/sites/agri.assembly.ca.gov/files/The%20Impact%20of%20Wildfires%20on%20California%20Agriculture%20Informational%20Hearing%20Report.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Cultivating Fear: The Vulnerability of Immigrant Farmworkers in the US to Sexual Violence and Sexual Harassment | HRW.” Human Rights Watch, 15 May 2012, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrw.org/report/2012/05/15/cultivating-fear/vulnerability-immigrant-farmworkers-us-sexual-violence-and&quot;&gt;https://www.hrw.org/report/2012/05/15/cultivating-fear/vulnerability-immigrant-farmworkers-us-sexual-violence-and&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“The Economic and Fiscal Consequences of Immigration.” The National Academies Press, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/23550/the-economic-and-fiscal-consequences-of-immigration&quot;&gt;https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/23550/the-economic-and-fiscal-consequences-of-immigration&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Farm Labor.” USDA ERS, 15 March 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ers.usda.gov/topics/farm-economy/farm-labor/&quot;&gt;https://www.ers.usda.gov/topics/farm-economy/farm-labor/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Immigrant Farmworkers and America’s Food Production - 5 Things to Know.” FWD.us, 14 September 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fwd.us/news/immigrant-farmworkers-and-americas-food-production-5-things-to-know/&quot;&gt;https://www.fwd.us/news/immigrant-farmworkers-and-americas-food-production-5-things-to-know/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Immigrants as Economic Contributors: Immigrants Fill the Temporary Needs of American Employers.” National Immigration Forum, &lt;a href=&quot;https://immigrationforum.org/article/immigrants-as-economic-contributors-immigrants-fill-the-temporary-needs-of-american-employers/&quot;&gt;https://immigrationforum.org/article/immigrants-as-economic-contributors-immigrants-fill-the-temporary-needs-of-american-employers/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Immigration Facts: The Positive Economic Impact Of Immigration.” FWD.us, 21 July 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fwd.us/news/immigration-facts-the-positive-economic-impact-of-immigration/&quot;&gt;https://www.fwd.us/news/immigration-facts-the-positive-economic-impact-of-immigration/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Issues Affecting Farm Workers - NFWM.” National Farm Worker Ministry, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nfwm.org/farm-workers/farm-worker-issues/&quot;&gt;https://nfwm.org/farm-workers/farm-worker-issues/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jordan, Miriam. “Farmworkers, Mostly Undocumented, Become ‘Essential’ During Pandemic.” The New York Times, 10 April 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/02/us/coronavirus-undocumented-immigrant-farmworkers-agriculture.html&quot;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/02/us/coronavirus-undocumented-immigrant-farmworkers-agriculture.html&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers.” U.S. Department of Labor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dol.gov/general/topic/training/migrantfarmworkers&quot;&gt;https://www.dol.gov/general/topic/training/migrantfarmworkers&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sherman, Arloc, et al. “Immigrants Contribute Greatly to U.S. Economy, Despite Administration’s “Public Charge” Rule Rationale.” Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, 15 August 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbpp.org/research/poverty-and-inequality/immigrants-contribute-greatly-to-us-economy-despite-administrations&quot;&gt;https://www.cbpp.org/research/poverty-and-inequality/immigrants-contribute-greatly-to-us-economy-despite-administrations&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Williamson, Molly Weston. “Protecting Farmworkers From Coronavirus and Securing the Food Supply.” Center for American Progress, 23 April 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogress.org/article/protecting-farmworkers-coronavirus-securing-food-supply/&quot;&gt;https://www.americanprogress.org/article/protecting-farmworkers-coronavirus-securing-food-supply/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 5 February 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Sophia Huang&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Mirabelle Jiang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sophia Huang</name></author><summary type="html">From the beginning Immigrants built America and continues to power it, making up more than a third of workers in some industries. They continue to improve our economy, creating companies around two times faster than American-born citizens. According to the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, immigrants added approximately $2 trillion to the United States’ GDP in 2016 while contributing around $458.7 billion to taxes in 2018. The National Immigration Forum reported that “employment-based immigrants are critical to the U.S. economy as they meet the temporary and permanent needs of U.S. employers in diverse industries”. The importance of immigrant workers is shown especially in terms of food production on our farms. However, despite their importance to our economy, these immigrant farm workers struggle to make ends meet as they face danger and are treated without concern for their wellbeing both on and off of the fields.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/grab.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gender Inequality in Industries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gender-inequality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gender Inequality in Industries" /><published>2023-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gender-inequality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gender-inequality/">&lt;p&gt;Gender equality in the workplace has been a concern since the 19th century. Since then, the number of working women has risen astronomical amounts. However, this change is not exclusively positive; with the idea of a male “sole provider” becoming more and more obsolete, the male presence in the workplace has diminished significantly. Since 2010, the number of women on payroll has surpassed that of men (Wall Street Journal). Through the number of men working in industries and, more specifically, education, the declining presence of men in the workplace is visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the 19th century, men were the only people in the workplace, yet this imbalance has drastically changed. While women have been pushing for equal rights and joining the workforce, the number of men considered to be in prime working age from 25-45 have been declining since the 60s (NPR). With the number of women on payroll being higher than that of men since 2010, there has been a lack of motivation to keep working for male workers. HEAL (health, education, administration, and literacy) had once been a male dominated area; now, the opposite now rests true. Due to this, there have been feeble attempts at encouraging men to keep working. However, not much has been done as men nowadays earn less than most men in 1979 (with inflation taken into account). Additionally, most men that are not working – whether teenagers or those in the prime working age – are not aware of this issue (NPR). These issues could stem from the education system, but not for the reasons one might think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education has had a major impact on the number of men in the workplace. Decades ago, teaching had been a male dominated profession; now only 1 in 10 high school teachers are male, partly due to the fact that it’s seen as a low reward profession (The Atlantic). This decline dates back to the 20th century, when in 1980, 40% of teachers were male; since then, the number has only gone down. Not seeing any men in the workplace while growing up contributes to the lack of motivation for males joining the workforce as well. Without anyone to relate to or consult, many men find it difficult to visualize their future in the workplace (NPR), especially when high schools rarely take the time and effort to display working men.
The number of men in the workforce has visibly declined tremendously in the past few decades due to the lack of motivation and education. Books like Richard Reeves’s Of Boys and Men have tried to tackle and bring awareness to this issue, however little has been done to resolve it. Men are struggling to find their place in the workplace, and the numbers of employed men in the prime working age needs to rise; if not, as the numbers keep going down, the presence of male workers will be non-existent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Hsu, Andrea. “Men Are Struggling. A New Book Explores Why and What to Do about It.” NPR, 4 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/11/04/1133586707/boys-men-labor-force-jobs- gender-gap-workforce&quot;&gt;https://www.npr.org/2022/11/04/1133586707/boys-men-labor-force-jobs- gender-gap-workforce&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Wong, Alia. “The U.S. Teaching Population Is Getting Bigger, and More Female.” The Atlantic, 20 Feb. 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2019/02/the-explosion-of -women-teachers/582622/&quot;&gt;https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2019/02/the-explosion-of -women-teachers/582622/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Omeokwe, Amara. “Women Overtake Men as Majority of U.S. Workforce.” Wall Street Journal, 10 Jan. 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/women-overtake-men-as-majority-of-u-s- workforce-11578670615&quot;&gt;https://www.wsj.com/articles/women-overtake-men-as-majority-of-u-s- workforce-11578670615&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Joyce Rizko&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Brian Yu and Annie Zhu&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joyce Rizko</name></author><summary type="html">Gender equality in the workplace has been a concern since the 19th century. Since then, the number of working women has risen astronomical amounts. However, this change is not exclusively positive; with the idea of a male “sole provider” becoming more and more obsolete, the male presence in the workplace has diminished significantly. Since 2010, the number of women on payroll has surpassed that of men (Wall Street Journal). Through the number of men working in industries and, more specifically, education, the declining presence of men in the workplace is visible.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/compare.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazon’s Worker’s Rights (or lack of them)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/amazon-worker-rights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazon's Worker's Rights (or lack of them)" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/amazon-worker-rights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/amazon-worker-rights/">&lt;p&gt;For years, Amazon has been at the forefront of controversy about the treatment of its workers. Though the company denies its infractions of workers rights, critics have exposed how detrimental these working conditions are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies by the Strategic Organizing Center note that Amazon’s “obsession with speed” puts the workers in danger. When workers fall under the pressure of meeting stringent production quotas, their risk of injury increases. Nearly one in five of Amazon’s delivery drivers suffered injuries in 2021. This injury rate alarmingly increased by 40% from last year’s. This obsession with speed is also apparent in the way that they strictly monitor their employees. Workers are constantly criticized for “idle time”, even if it lasts for just a few minutes. An Amazon spokesman has revealed: “Performance is only measured when an employee is at their station and logged in to do their job.” However, Darren Westwood, an Amazon worker, highly condemns these policies. He has revealed his distress about how even his bathroom breaks are tracked and the way that managers constantly question him about his idle time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon had aspired to control its workers even further by patenting a design for a wristband that tracks the workers’ locations and “nudging” them in the direction of their next assignment, creating a tight schedule and toxic work environment. Due to ethical issues, Amazon abandoned this patent, but the spirit of this bizarre concept lives on. Recently, on December 27 2022, 61-year-old Rick Jacobs died at the Amazon DEN4 warehouse in Colorado Springs, Colorado, yet instead of moving the body, managers created a makeshift barrier around the deceased worker using cardboard bins, outrageously claiming that this act would avoid distracting other employees from work. Witnesses were shocked by the “blatant disregard of human emotions at this facility”. An anonymous worker discloses: “No one should have been told to work alongside a dead body, particularly after witnessing it…[we received] no warnings before walking into the building”. Another asks: “Do you think we could not have had a little respect and shut down long enough to at least get the body out of the facility and clean up after him before people are milling around like nothing’s happening?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon’s disregard for the well-being of its workers also applies economically. On January 25, 2023, Amazon warehouse workers in rhe UK staged their first-ever strike over pay and working conditions. Staff were angered with the pay increase of just 50 pence per hour. Workers claim that the 5% pay increase fails to match the inflation of living costs and want a minimum £15 an hour. Some of the staff are working up to 60 hours a week just so they can meet mortgage payments. Westwood revealed to CNBC: “Someone the other day said we’re treated like robots—no, robots are treated better”. Bogdan, another participant in the strike, said that this extremely low pay offer insulted staff. He chose to join the strike because he wanted the public to “understand what is going on” behind the scenes every time they choose the convenience of Amazon. Though Amazon attempts to cover up these situations and portray themselves as a perfect corporation, one must accept that these events are a reality that threaten workers rights to safety and economic stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sanato, Michael. “‘Lack of Respect’: Outcry over Amazon Employee’s Death on Warehouse Floor.” The Guardian, Guardian News and Media, 9 Jan. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://amp.theguardian.com/technology/2023/jan/09/amazon-employee-death-warehouse-floor-colorado&quot;&gt;https://amp.theguardian.com/technology/2023/jan/09/amazon-employee-death-warehouse-floor-colorado&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Browne, Ryan. “’Robots Are Treated Better’: Amazon Warehouse Workers Stage First-Ever Strike in the UK.” CNBC, CNBC, 26 Jan. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2023/01/25/amazon-workers-stage-first-ever-strike-in-the-uk-over-pay-working-conditions.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2023/01/25/amazon-workers-stage-first-ever-strike-in-the-uk-over-pay-working-conditions.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jordan, Dearbail, and Zoe Conway. “Amazon Strikes: Workers Claim Their Toilet Breaks Are Timed.” BBC News, BBC, 25 Jan. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/business-64384287.amp&quot;&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/business-64384287.amp&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Dawood, Sarah. “Amazon’s Worker Surveillance ‘Leads to Extreme Stress and Anxiety.’” New Statesman, New Statesman, 4 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newstatesman.com/spotlight/cybersecurity/2022/11/amazon-worker-surveillance-extreme-stress-anxiety&quot;&gt;https://www.newstatesman.com/spotlight/cybersecurity/2022/11/amazon-worker-surveillance-extreme-stress-anxiety&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“’Grueling’: Amazon Workers Describe What It’s like Working Peak Season.” VICE, VICE, 15 Dec. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/wxna3q/grueling-amazon-workers-describe-what-its-like-working-peak-season&quot;&gt;https://www.vice.com/en/article/wxna3q/grueling-amazon-workers-describe-what-its-like-working-peak-season&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Annierpalmer. “Amazon Faces Probe by Federal Prosecutors and OSHA into Warehouse Safety.” CNBC, CNBC, 19 July 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2022/07/18/amazon-faces-probe-by-federal-prosecutors-osha-into-warehouse-safety.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2022/07/18/amazon-faces-probe-by-federal-prosecutors-osha-into-warehouse-safety.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Annierpalmer. “Nearly One in Five Amazon Delivery Drivers Suffered Injuries in 2021, Study Finds.” CNBC, CNBC, 24 May 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/05/24/study-nearly-one-in-five-amazon-drivers-suffered-injuries-in-2021.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/05/24/study-nearly-one-in-five-amazon-drivers-suffered-injuries-in-2021.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Aava Ghorbanian&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Sophia Zhou&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aava Ghorbanian</name></author><summary type="html">For years, Amazon has been at the forefront of controversy about the treatment of its workers. Though the company denies its infractions of workers rights, critics have exposed how detrimental these working conditions are.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/amazon.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">South African Erosion of Workers’ Rights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/south-african-erosion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="South African Erosion of Workers’ Rights" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/south-african-erosion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/south-african-erosion/">&lt;p&gt;The single-room tin homes of South Africa’s 500+ townships are testaments to the radical inequality that remains as a legacy of Apartheid, South Africa’s past oppressive system of government which enforced racial segregation. Almost 30 years post-Apartheid, South African wealth distribution is still vastly unequal. The various attempts to redistribute wealth have created a slightly more diverse yet still highly exclusive upper economic echelon which excludes the vast majority of the population. Adding on to the concerning economic and social status of South Africa, jobs are scarce with the unemployment rate at around 43% and people are desperate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, any work is coveted by those trapped in poverty, and competition for job slots is immense. This desperation facilitates the exploitation of economically disadvantaged South Africans, and the rendering of labour laws null and void. There are three major reasons for this: the desperation of the workers, the wage of labour, and the weak South African government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, in South Africa, there are a number of labour laws meant to implement a meaningful minimum wage and protect menial labour workers. However, a vast number of labourers are desperate enough to work for anything and as a result, the sanctity of labour laws is largely non-existent. Many workers will accept short-term work which brings in cash quickly, but are not sustainable jobs. As such, employers don’t feel the same level of responsibility for the wellbeing of their employees, and often get away with underpaying and overworking individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, there is an issue surrounding the culture of menial labour in South Africa - there is a running joke among immigrants from first world countries that labour is “free”, because the comparative price of having three full time domestic workers barely begins to reach the cost of hiring an au-pair to watch your children for a week in the US. Consequently, almost all South African middle and upper class households will employ at least one full time worker to do tasks from cleaning the house to raising the children. These low standards of payment for domestic workers and with a set minimum wage of R23.19 (less than $1.40), has made it very difficult to reshape salaries for South African manual labourers. As a result, escaping poverty is highly unlikely and extremely hard for workers, even with a full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the South African government has largely failed in the implementation of labour laws. The South African justice system fails frequently, making it one of the crime capitals of the world. Additionally, government efficiency is significantly hindered by endemic corruption, which fuels policy decisions that are often more advantageous for government officials than they are for citizens. Consequently, mistreatment of employees and strong-arming employees into silence to disincentivize legal action and accountability has become the norm, and the mechanisms in place designed to deal with this are often inaccessible or ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worker rights in South Africa, while somewhat enshrined in law, have been forgotten or abused in practice, an issue which has existed for much of South Africa’s dark history and remains as a part of the legacy of a deeply divided state. The path forward for South Africa is a long one, and will require a shift in the way the country views labour and values upliftment of disadvantaged communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://businesstech.co.za/news/trending/586360/government-says-south-africans-are-failing-domestic-workers-heres-how-much-you-should-be-paying-them/&quot;&gt;https://businesstech.co.za/news/trending/586360/government-says-south-africans-are-failing-domestic-workers-heres-how-much-you-should-be-paying-them/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.news24.com/fin24/opinion/opinion-labour-law-for-domestic-workers-explained-20220510&quot;&gt;https://www.news24.com/fin24/opinion/opinion-labour-law-for-domestic-workers-explained-20220510&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alrei.org/education/a-report-on-the-working-and-living-conditions-of-domestic-workers-in-south-africa-for-alrei-compiled-by-hameda-deedat&quot;&gt;https://alrei.org/education/a-report-on-the-working-and-living-conditions-of-domestic-workers-in-south-africa-for-alrei-compiled-by-hameda-deedat&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Frankie Lewittton&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Sophia Huang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frankie Lewittton</name></author><summary type="html">The single-room tin homes of South Africa’s 500+ townships are testaments to the radical inequality that remains as a legacy of Apartheid, South Africa’s past oppressive system of government which enforced racial segregation. Almost 30 years post-Apartheid, South African wealth distribution is still vastly unequal. The various attempts to redistribute wealth have created a slightly more diverse yet still highly exclusive upper economic echelon which excludes the vast majority of the population. Adding on to the concerning economic and social status of South Africa, jobs are scarce with the unemployment rate at around 43% and people are desperate.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/iran_timeline.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Minimum Wage Sick Days and the Problems With Worker’s Rights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minimum-wage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minimum Wage Sick Days and the Problems With Worker's Rights" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minimum-wage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minimum-wage/">&lt;p&gt;Though we view the United States as a whole, labor laws vary from state to state, and many simply chalk these variances up to differences in political parties. Yet, labor laws in blue-dominated states do not necessarily trump those of the red ones. The upshot: no matter the political party, most states fall well short of offering workers the rights they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take minimum wage for example. In New York, a traditionally blue state, workers must make a minimum of $14.20 per hour, while in Texas, a traditionally red state, the minimum wage is $7.25 an hour. The latter seems particularly low. Minimum wage workers in Texas make an average of $58 a day, with their salary totaling around $15,080 per year – well below MIT’s designated livable wage of $34,132.80 for a single adult without children in Texas. However, the situation in New York isn’t much better. A minimum wage worker there would make $29,536 a year, which is still far below the livable wage of $44,636.80. When taking into account living expenses, New York and Texas are not so different after all – both fail to provide the minimum to support their residents’ livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wages are not the only problem at hand for workers. Sick days are also an essential part of having a stable job, as anyone who caught Covid during the past three years knows well. In Texas, workers are not legally entitled to sick days and are not compensated for them. Surprisingly, this fact is true for workers in New York state as well and seems particularly problematic, considering the low wages and high living expenses that residents of the state face. The absence of paid leave forces workers to choose between staying home while sick or making enough money to get by – options that are impossible to pick between. Obviously, problems with workers’ rights are found in both Democratic and Republican states and go much deeper than political affiliation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common misconception of labor laws is that they are regulated better in blue states than in red states, but a simple comparison of New York and Texas quickly debunks this idea. The reason for this is that, most often, the cost of living is not taken into consideration when looking at a minimum wage. Even though we view New York as a very liberal state, the disparities between income and spending show that the state must do better to ensure that workers are treated fairly.
Of course, that goes for Texas too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Living Wage Calculator - Living Wage Calculation for Texas.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://livingwage.mit.edu/states/48&quot;&gt;https://livingwage.mit.edu/states/48&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Living Wage Calculator - Living Wage Calculation for New York County, New York.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://livingwage.mit.edu/counties/36061&quot;&gt;https://livingwage.mit.edu/counties/36061&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;​​Manager, Website. “New York Labor Law: The Ultimate Guide 2020.” Cilenti &amp;amp; Cooper - Overtime
Lawyers in NY, 12 Jan. 2021
&lt;a href=&quot;https://wagefirm.com/new-york-labor-law-the-ultimate-guide/#:~:text=The%20basic%20rights%20all%20workers,rest%20and%20scheduled%20work%20breaks&quot;&gt;https://wagefirm.com/new-york-labor-law-the-ultimate-guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Homebase. “State Labor Law - Texas.” Homebase, 14 Jan. 2023
&lt;a href=&quot;https://joinhomebase.com/state-labor-laws/texas/&quot;&gt;https://joinhomebase.com/state-labor-laws/texas/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Homebase. “State Labor Law - New York.” Homebase, 4 May 2022
&lt;a href=&quot;https://joinhomebase.com/state-labor-laws/new-york&quot;&gt;https://joinhomebase.com/state-labor-laws/new-york/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Eliška Levisohn&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Brian Yu, Mirabelle Jiang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Eliška Levisohn</name></author><summary type="html">Though we view the United States as a whole, labor laws vary from state to state, and many simply chalk these variances up to differences in political parties. Yet, labor laws in blue-dominated states do not necessarily trump those of the red ones. The upshot: no matter the political party, most states fall well short of offering workers the rights they need.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/rights.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Inequalities in the AI industry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ai-industry-inequality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inequalities in the AI industry" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ai-industry-inequality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ai-industry-inequality/">&lt;p&gt;The AI industry, like many technology sectors, has faced criticism for a lack of diversity and unequal treatment of certain groups. This can manifest in a variety of ways, such as diversity and inclusion, bias in AI systems, and job automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AI industry has a significant lack of diversity, especially in leadership positions and technical roles. This leads to a homogeneous culture and limited perspectives in the development and deployment of AI systems. Research has shown that the AI workforce is predominantly male and from certain ethnic and cultural backgrounds, which can lead to bias in the development and deployment of AI systems. To address this problem, many companies and organizations are taking steps to increase diversity and inclusivity in the AI industry, such as through initiatives aimed at recruiting and retaining underrepresented groups and promoting equal opportunities in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increasing use of AI and automation technologies in various industries has led to job automation, where tasks previously performed by humans are now being carried out by machines or algorithms. While this has brought many benefits, such as increased efficiency and lower costs, it has also had an impact on employment, as some jobs are becoming obsolete. However, it is important to note that AI and automation are also creating new jobs in fields such as data science, machine learning, and software development. Additionally, some experts believe that AI could potentially enhance existing jobs by allowing workers to focus on more creative and higher-value tasks. Nevertheless, the impact of AI and automation on employment is a complex issue that requires ongoing attention and investment in workforce development and training programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bias in AI systems refers to the phenomenon where an algorithm or model shows unfair or discriminatory behavior towards certain groups of people based on factors such as race, gender, age, or socioeconomic status. This can occur due to a number of reasons, such as the use of biased data in training models, the choice of algorithms or features that reinforce existing biases, or the lack of diversity among the individuals developing and deploying the AI systems. Bias in AI systems can have serious consequences, including discrimination in areas such as hiring, lending, and criminal justice. To address this problem, it is important to have diverse teams working on AI development and deployment, to use unbiased training data, and to regularly evaluate and test AI systems for bias. There is also a growing body of research in the field of fair AI, which aims to develop methods for creating AI systems that are equitable and unbiased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is a divide between those who have access to AI technologies and those who do not, the widening of the digital divide and unequal distribution of the benefits of AI will surely. Unequal access to AI technologies refers to the unequal distribution of resources and opportunities for individuals and organizations to use and benefit from AI. This can be due to factors such as geographic location, financial resources, technical expertise, and access to data, leading to disparities in the development and deployment of AI solutions. The lack of equal access to AI technologies can result in a widening of the digital divide and exacerbate existing socio-economic inequalities. Addressing this challenge requires collaboration and investment from governments, private organizations, and the wider AI community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing these inequalities in the AI industry requires a concerted effort from all stakeholders, including companies, governments, and communities, to promote diversity and inclusion, provide reskilling and job opportunities, reduce bias in AI systems, and ensure equitable access to AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Joyce Wang&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Shiksha Anand&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joyce Wang</name></author><summary type="html">The AI industry, like many technology sectors, has faced criticism for a lack of diversity and unequal treatment of certain groups. This can manifest in a variety of ways, such as diversity and inclusion, bias in AI systems, and job automation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/robot.png" /></entry></feed>