<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-31T17:34:55-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Our Generation</title><subtitle>This is homepage for SHS Our Generation Club.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Letter from the Editors in Chief</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/editor-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letter from the Editors in Chief" /><published>2023-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-editor-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/editor-words/">&lt;p&gt;Hello, we’re the Editors in Chief of Our Gen! Thank you for reading the March 2023 issue of Our Gen. Our goal for our club is to connect the teenagers in our current digital age to major current issues to help us further understand and care about the world around us. As writers, artists, and editors, our team has delved into current issues, connecting them back to our lives. Understanding earthquakes in Turkey is extremely important, and so is understanding how the natural fundamental environmental issue is affecting the entire world, including our homes. For example, California fault lines provide a dangerous possibility for earthquakes up to a magnitude of eight. In cases such as this, we believe that it is important to educate teenagers about these natural disasters so we can better protect ourselves and perhaps, one day, to be able to protect the human race from those deadly disasters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to thank our amazing team for their hard work on this issue, our advisor Mrs. Chung for her constant support, and a special thank you to Ms.Tekin for inspiring us to take action and to influence others regarding the Turkey earthquakes. Our Generation reminds us how closely connected people are, and how even a small positive remark can leave a huge trace in someone’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this, we hope our readers will take away the importance of understanding our world. Our Generation creates a platform for teenagers to utilize their voices and actions. Even more so, we would like to encourage and empower young adults to become agents of change and to make those positive impacts for our society. We, young adults, can shape the future. We are the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br /&gt;
Chanah Y. &amp;amp; Melody Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-kahramanmaras-earthquake&quot;&gt;The Kahramanmaras Earthquake&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Annie Zhu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 6th, 2023, two devastating earthquakes struck Turkey at its Syrian border. Following the first magnitude 7.8 earthquake, another magnitude 7.5 earthquake hit nine hours later. Thousands of people were killed and billions of dollars were lost from physical damage. The state authorities urgently declared a level 4 emergency and called for international assistance while the death toll climbed rapidly. To date, more than 9.1 million people have been affected, and more than 45,000 people were killed in this incident. By March 1, 2023, more than 11,000 aftershocks in the region have also added to the devastation. This earthquake is one of the largest in Turkey’s history, along with the 1668 North Anatolia earthquake and the 1939 Erzincan earthquake. One thing is certain – the destructive consequences of the event will remain for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of the Kahramanmaras earthquake has had severe negative effects on physical and mental health of the residents in Turkey and Syria. Since the quake on February 6th, 1.9 million people have relocated and now live in temporary shelters after the disaster destroyed their houses. These poor living conditions make the survivors susceptible to health issues. Physical effects aside, the experience has led people to develop trauma and increased risk for chronic anxiety and depression. For instance, the survivors may develop Survivor’s Guilt as they believe that they have done something wrong when others have passed away in the tragic event. Furthermore, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake directly damaged $34.2 billion worth of buildings and facilities in Türkiye and Syria. This also exposed the design problems in buildings that were vulnerable to strong earthquakes, leading to more destruction due to anthropogenic factors. Ultimately, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake contributed to a large humanitarian crisis and caused economic problems that are affecting the lives of millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to the Kahramanmaras Earthquake, countries around the world have offered humanitarian support to relieve the level of destruction. For example, the United Nations have offered multiple cross-border aid operations to deliver supplies. The Bab Al-Hawa, Bab Al-Salam, and Al-Ra’ee have all been open for UN aid delivery, and by March 4th, 583 trucks with aid have crossed into Northwest Syria to provide assistance. However, according to an IFRC market assessment, hot meals, hygiene items, winter clothes, and many more critical necessities are still desperately needed in the affected areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, being one of the worst earthquakes in recent years, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake has transformed the lives of many and is continuously affecting more. Similar to many other large-scale earthquakes in history, it destroyed local communities, the economy, and killed thousands of people. In addition to learning the details about how this earthquake has affected Türkiye and Syria and how the United States plays a role in this event, this issue also introduces past earthquakes that have heavily injured communities around the world. By learning about the history of earthquakes and juxtaposing different earthquakes for comparison, we will discuss the multifaceted impact of natural disasters in a comprehensive manner. From the effect on people’s mental health to global climate change, understanding the context beyond the Kahramanmaras Earthquake is essential for teenagers to provide better assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://disasterphilanthropy.org/disasters/2023-turkey-syria-earthquake/&quot;&gt;2023 Turkey-Syria Earthquake - Center for Disaster Philanthropy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reliefweb.int/report/turkiye/turkiye-2023-earthquakes-situation-report-no-6-3-march-2023&quot;&gt;Türkiye: 2023 Earthquakes Situation Report No. 6, As of 3 March 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/survivors-of-deadly-earthquakes-must-deal-with-lasting-trauma/&quot;&gt;Survivors of Deadly Earthquakes Must Deal with Lasting Trauma - Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Annie Zhu&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chanah Yin, Melody Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Hello, we’re the Editors in Chief of Our Gen! Thank you for reading the March 2023 issue of Our Gen. Our goal for our club is to connect the teenagers in our current digital age to major current issues to help us further understand and care about the world around us. As writers, artists, and editors, our team has delved into current issues, connecting them back to our lives. Understanding earthquakes in Turkey is extremely important, and so is understanding how the natural fundamental environmental issue is affecting the entire world, including our homes. For example, California fault lines provide a dangerous possibility for earthquakes up to a magnitude of eight. In cases such as this, we believe that it is important to educate teenagers about these natural disasters so we can better protect ourselves and perhaps, one day, to be able to protect the human race from those deadly disasters.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/INTROIMAGE_frontpage.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of Earthquakes Around the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/History-of-Earthquake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of Earthquakes Around the World" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-History-of-Earthquake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/History-of-Earthquake/">&lt;p&gt;Small earthquakes are quite common worldwide; a million or so happen each year. However, certain places are more susceptible to earthquakes due to their location near the seven major tectonic plates. As countries in those areas have continued to develop, new technologies lessen the damage and give citizens earthquake warnings, lowering mortality rates. So although high-magnitude earthquakes remain dangerous, the amount of damage they inflict is dependent on access to technologies to prevent earthquakes and governmental measures taken towards minimizing the dame of earthquakes. This is shown through the comparison of Japan and Haiti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Haiti experienced a magnitude 7.0 earthquake that killed around 222,570 people. According to the Earthquake Magnitude Scale, an earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 is considered a major earthquake but is not at the magnitude of other very destructive earthquakes. Still, the Haitian Earthquake had one of the highest death tolls from any earthquake in the 21st century. One of the reasons for this tragedy is the disorganization and lack of standardization in buildings in Haiti. When the 2010 earthquake hit, there was no early warning for its citizens. Also, there is no “national building code” enforced by the government, says Fouche, a Haitian earthquake engineer. The economic state in Haiti also played a role in why this earthquake was so deadly. Most people cannot afford newer technology developed to help lessen the impact of earthquakes, like shock absorption in buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Japan, because of its economic wealth, there are now buildings that have been designed with base isolators that allow a building to move from side to side while remaining standing during an earthquake. The government also has earthquake-resistant standards for new buildings and an early warning system to notify the citizens when there is an earthquake. A combination of effective warning and new technology is why when a 9.1 earthquake then tsunami happened in Japan, there were 11 times fewer deaths, even though the earthquake in Japan had a much high magnitude. These advancements have caused earthquakes in Japan to have fairly low mortality rates in recent years but have also helped prevent the amount of property damage from earthquakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, earthquake magnitude, economic wealth, and government stability all contribute to the amount of damage that such a natural disaster will inflict upon a country. As the methods for earthquake damage control develop and become accessible, we hope all countries at risk of earthquakes will eventually be able to protect all of their citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Joyce, Christopher. “Haiti’s Buildings Weren’t Fit to Withstand Quakes.” NPR, NPR, 14 Jan. 2010, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2010/01/14/122547242/haitis-buildings-werent-fit-to-withstand-quakes.&quot;&gt;https://www.npr.org/2010/01/14/122547242/haitis-buildings-werent-fit-to-withstand-quakes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Fuller, Thomas, et al. “Buildings Can Be Designed to Withstand Earthquakes. Why Doesn’t the U.S. Build More of Them?” The New York Times, The New York Times, 4 June 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/03/us/earthquake-preparedness-usa-japan.html&quot;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/03/us/earthquake-preparedness-usa-japan.htm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Lists of 21st-Century Earthquakes.” Wikipedia, Wikimedia Foundation, 10 Mar. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_21st-century_earthquakes#cite_note-FOOTNOTEISC2022-6&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_21st-century_earthquakes#cite_note-FOOTNOTEISC2022-6&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Where Do Earthquakes Occur?” British Geological Survey, 9 Dec. 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bgs.ac.uk/discovering-geology/earth-hazards/earthquakes/where-do-earthquakes-occur/#:~:text=Over%2080%20per%20cent%20of,active%20zone%20in%20the%20world&quot;&gt;https://www.bgs.ac.uk/discovering-geology/earth-hazards/earthquakes/where-do-earthquakes-occur&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Earthquake Magnitude Scale.” Michigan Technological University, Michigan Technological University, 4 Oct. 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mtu.edu/geo/community/seismology/learn/earthquake-measure/magnitude/&quot;&gt;https://www.mtu.edu/geo/community/seismology/learn/earthquake-measure/magnitude/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Eliška Levisohn&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Eliška Levisohn</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Small earthquakes are quite common worldwide; a million or so happen each year. However, certain places are more susceptible to earthquakes due to their location near the seven major tectonic plates. As countries in those areas have continued to develop, new technologies lessen the damage and give citizens earthquake warnings, lowering mortality rates. So although high-magnitude earthquakes remain dangerous, the amount of damage they inflict is dependent on access to technologies to prevent earthquakes and governmental measures taken towards minimizing the dame of earthquakes. This is shown through the comparison of Japan and Haiti.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/History%20of%20Earthquakes%20around%20the%20world.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Impacts of Earthquakes in Turkey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impacts of Earthquakes in Turkey" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey/">&lt;p&gt;On February 6th, 2023, Turkey was hit by a powerful earthquake with a magnitude of 6.9. It struck the eastern province of Van, causing extensive damage to buildings and infrastructure and claiming the lives of at least 45,000 people. The impacts of the earthquake were widespread and impacted many civilians. Many residents were left homeless, without access to necessities such as food or clean water. The earthquake triggered landslides and rockfalls, making rescue efforts difficult and dangerous for first responders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite those effects, one of the most devastating impacts of the earthquake was the high death toll. As rescue teams worked to search and uncover survivors from the fallen rubble, the death toll continued to hike up. The number of people affected was even worse than normal, because the earthquake hit in the early hours of the morning, catching many residents off guard and trapping them inside their homes. As a result, many people were unable to escape in time and were buried alive. In addition, the earthquake caused significant damage to infrastructure. Homes, schools, hospitals, and other buildings were destroyed or badly damaged. The earthquake also caused major disruptions to transportation, making it difficult for emergency responders to reach affected areas and for residents to access aid and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earthquake also had a significant economic impact on the region, with many businesses and industries affected by the destruction of infrastructure and the loss of lives. The region is known for its agriculture and livestock industries, both of which were severely impacted by the earthquake. The destruction of homes and buildings also led to a decline in tourism, which is a major source of income for the region. The World Bank’s Disaster Assessment Report estimates that the damage caused by the earthquake will total up to more than $34 billion dollars. The earthquake had a psychological impact on the residents of the affected areas. Many residents were traumatized by the experience and were left feeling vulnerable and uncertain about their future. The loss of loved ones and the destruction of homes and communities left residents struggling to cope with the aftermath of the earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the earthquake, there have been calls for increased investment in disaster preparedness and management in Turkey and around the world. While it is impossible to predict or prevent natural disasters, taking proactive measures to prepare for them can help to minimize the loss of life and damage to infrastructure. This includes investing in early warning systems, training for emergency responders, and ensuring that critical infrastructure is designed and built to withstand the impacts of natural disasters. The loss and damage of the earthquake will forever serve as a reminder of the importance of disaster preparedness and management in reducing the impact of natural disasters. As we move towards the future, hopefully, the new preparations learned from this experience will improve our response towards future similarly devastating earthquakes and allow us to preserve more lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Akgun, A. A., &amp;amp; Vaněk, J. (2023, March 9). Earthquake in Turkey exposes gap between seismic knowledge and action – but it is possible to prepare. The Conversation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/earthquake-in-turkey-exposes-gap-between-seismic-knowledge-and-action-but-it-is-possible-to-prepare-199379&quot;&gt;https://theconversation.com/earthquake-in-turkey-exposes-gap-between-seismic-knowledge-and-action-but-it-is-possible-to-prepare-199379&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;“Earthquake Damage in Türkiye Estimated to Exceed $34 billion.” World Bank, 27 February 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2023/02/27/earthquake-damage-in-turkiye-estimated-to-exceed-34-billion-world-bank-disaster-assessment-report&quot;&gt;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2023/02/27/earthquake-damage-in-turkiye-estimated-to-exceed-34-billion-world-bank-disaster-assessment-report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Accessed 18 March 2023. Mime, M. (2023, March 6). The economic cost of Turkey’s earthquake could be as high as $15 billion. CNN. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/06/middleeast/turkey-earthquake-economic-cost-mime-intl/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/06/middleeast/turkey-earthquake-economic-cost-mime-intl/index.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Turkey earthquake: More than 100 dead as 6.9-magnitude quake hits Van. (2023, February 6). BBC News. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-64824516&quot;&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-64824516&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;U.S. Geological Survey. (n.d.). M6.9 - Eastern Turkey. Retrieved March 10, 2023, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/map/?extent=-46.67959,-80.15625&amp;amp;extent=63.39152,116.71875&amp;amp;listOnlyShown=true&quot;&gt;https://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/map/?extent=-46.67959,-80.15625&amp;amp;extent=63.39152,116.71875&amp;amp;listOnlyShown=true&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Sophia Huang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sophia Huang</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">On February 6th, 2023, Turkey was hit by a powerful earthquake with a magnitude of 6.9. It struck the eastern province of Van, causing extensive damage to buildings and infrastructure and claiming the lives of at least 45,000 people. The impacts of the earthquake were widespread and impacted many civilians. Many residents were left homeless, without access to necessities such as food or clean water. The earthquake triggered landslides and rockfalls, making rescue efforts difficult and dangerous for first responders.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Impacts%20of%20the%20Earthquakes%20in%20Turkey.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comparison of Turkey and California Earthquakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Compare-Earthquake-California/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparison of Turkey and California Earthquakes" /><published>2023-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Compare-Earthquake-California</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Compare-Earthquake-California/">&lt;p&gt;Earthquakes prove to be one of the most unique and dangerous natural disasters due to their unpredictability and invisibility. While people do not consistently fear them, even the slightest tremor can lead to panic, especially near fault lines. Fault lines, or the boundaries between tectonic plates, mark the areas that are prone to violent earthquakes. California and Turkey have some of the most relevant fault lines, with the former’s infamous San Andreas Fault and the latter’s North Anatolian Fault. Both fault lines, while similar in some aspects, hold their own secrets and dangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geologists classify the San Andreas Fault as a slip-strike fault, due to the way the Northern Pacific and North American plates collide. The former collides against the latter in a way that is also classified as a right-lateral fault. The SAF extends over 800 miles – about 14,080 football fields – from the Gulf of California to around San Francisco. While no reliable way of predicting seismic activity exists, researchers have noticed that an earthquake of about magnitude 6.0 comes every 22 years. The most recent ones have been in 2004 with a magnitude of 6.0 and 1989 with a magnitude of 6.9. The latter especially caused significant damage in areas like Monterey; it resulted in about 60 deaths, thousands of casualties, and billions of dollars in damages. It is also worth noting that not only is the earthquake itself extremely dangerous and deadly, but the aftershocks too. These may come moments or even days after the original earthquake and catch people by surprise. The San Andreas Fault produces some of the most deadly earthquakes, not unlike recent seismic activity in Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The North Anatolian Fault falls in the same category as the San Andreas Fault; it too is a slip-strike and right-lateral fault. The collision happens between the Eurasion and Anatolian-Aegean plates. The NAF’s size rivals the SAF’s, as it stretches over the Marmara Sea well into the east of Turkey. The transform’s irregular seismic activity leaves no hint of when the next earthquake can occur. The last earthquakes in 2022 had a magnitude of 6.1 and the ones in 1999 had a magnitude of 7.2. The most recent earthquakes significantly extended the fault line westward into the Marmara Sea, which exponentially increases the areas impacted whenever an earthquake occurs. The North Anatolian Fault’s unpredictability and immense size means it has the potential to produce a deadly earthquake at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The San Andreas Fault and North Anatolian Fault are both active fault lines with sizes that surpass most others. With a history of incredibly high magnitude earthquakes, both leave neary-inhabitants cautious and wary of incoming activity. To combat this, California, Turkey, and other countries at risk of high-magnitude earthquakes have been working to boost infrastructure and figure out ways to minimize damage. For example, students undergo earthquake drills in order to be informed of what to do in the case of a disaster. The SAF and NAF are forces to be reckoned with, and their mere presence is enough to leave people with a sense of unease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Andrei, Mihai. “The San Andreas Fault — What It Is, Why It Matters, and What You Should Know about Its Earthquakes.” ZME Science, 26 Oct. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zmescience.com/science/the-san-andreas-fault-what-it-is-why-it-matters-and-what-you-should-know-about-its-earthquakes/&quot;&gt;https://www.zmescience.com/science/the-san-andreas-fault-what-it-is-why-it-matters-and-what-you-should-know-about-its-earthquakes/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 7 March 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Britannica, The Editors of Encyclopaedia. “San Andreas Fault”. Encyclopedia Britannica, 12 Jan. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/place/San-Andreas-Fault&quot;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/place/San-Andreas-Fault&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 7 March 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Joyce Rizko&lt;br /&gt;
Editted by Raquel Rybakova&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joyce Rizko</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Earthquakes prove to be one of the most unique and dangerous natural disasters due to their unpredictability and invisibility. While people do not consistently fear them, even the slightest tremor can lead to panic, especially near fault lines. Fault lines, or the boundaries between tectonic plates, mark the areas that are prone to violent earthquakes. California and Turkey have some of the most relevant fault lines, with the former’s infamous San Andreas Fault and the latter’s North Anatolian Fault. Both fault lines, while similar in some aspects, hold their own secrets and dangers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/TurkeyandCaliforniaEarthquakes.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Turkey-Syria Earthquake and Its Impact on Mental Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Earthquake-impact-Mental-Health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turkey-Syria Earthquake and Its Impact on Mental Health" /><published>2023-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Earthquake-impact-Mental-Health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Earthquake-impact-Mental-Health/">&lt;p&gt;On February 6, 2023, a catastrophic earthquake changed the lives of millions of people in Turkey and Syria. This earthquake resulted in a death toll of more than 50,000 people, while leaving millions more people homeless. This 7.8 magnitude earthquake will not only lead to years of rebuilding, but also mental health problems for those who survived. Mental health issues are prevalent all around the world. In America, nearly 20% of all adults suffer some form of mental illness with 10 million of them suffering severe mental illness. When someone experiences trauma, they become more vulnerable to developing mental illnesses, making the issue even more prevalent
A study on the 2010 Canterbury earthquake in New Zealand found that there was an association between increased rates of disorder and increased rates of exposure to trauma. Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), anxiety levels, nicotine addiction, and overall disorders all increased for survivors after the earthquake, and they could last for up to seven years after the earthquake. The severity of the illness also results from many factors. For example, people who live in poorer regions of a city are more likely to have trauma because the poorer infrastructure leads to more destruction. This means that there are more people in the area who are suffering and dying, contributing to that trauma. This is especially true in many regions in Turkey and Syria, where they do not have the buildings like Japan that are designed to withstand strong earthquakes as a result of all the time and money spent to ensure their buildings can be used again after an earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the victims of the earthquake, children are especially vulnerable to trauma. They can experience long term anxiety, trouble sleeping, and changes in behavior or attitude, which impacts their physical growth and development. Other signs of mental trauma include stomach aches, nightmares, nausea, trouble concentrating and more. While the symptoms may not linger, an incident or conversation that reminds them of the trauma can easily trigger the symptoms again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand the impact of trauma on a person, one must look at how it affects the brain. The brain consists of many regions, three which are significantly impacted by trauma. First, the amygdala, which plays a role in emotions like fear. If it senses an external stress factor in the surroundings, it perceives it as a threat and arouses the emotion of fear. Those with PTSD have increased activity in their amygdala, leading to constant stress and anxiety. Second, the hippocampus is used for storing and retrieving memories in the brain. They can vividly remember these traumatic experiences, causing fear and stress even if they are in a safe environment. Third, the prefrontal cortex is in charge of regulating emotions, and it is forced to work overtime to counteract the negative emotions coming from the amygdala, resulting in those with trauma struggling to control their emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, people who were directly affected by the earthquake have an increased risk of developing mental illness. However, those who are reading about the earthquake on mainstream media may also experience feeling overwhelmed or useless. For these cases, the best solution is to step away from the internet, reflect on inner emotions, and research ways to help those affected by the earthquake. While all this may seem depressing, the bright side is that PTSD can lead to growth and development within people. They become more resilient, form new relationships and perspectives along the way, which would accompany them for the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Beaglehole B;Boden JM;Bell C;Mulder RT;Dhakal B;Horwood LJ; “The Long-Term Impacts of the Canterbury Earthquakes on the Mental Health of the Christchurch Health and Development Study Cohort.” The Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry, U.S. National Library of Medicine, 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36448198/&quot;&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36448198/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Earthquakes in Turkey and Syria: What Is MSF Doing?” Doctors Without Borders - USA, 6 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doctorswithoutborders.org/latest/msf-responds-overwhelming-medical-needs-following-earthquakes-turkey-and-syria&quot;&gt;https://www.doctorswithoutborders.org/latest/msf-responds-overwhelming-medical-needs-following-earthquakes-turkey-and-syria&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Lewis, Tanya. “Survivors of Deadly Earthquakes Must Deal with Lasting Trauma.” Scientific American, Scientific American, 17 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/survivors-of-deadly-earthquakes-must-deal-with-lasting-trauma&quot;&gt;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/survivors-of-deadly-earthquakes-must-deal-with-lasting-trauma/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Osman, Nadda. “Turkey-Syria Earthquake: The Mental Health Impact of Natural Disaster.” Middle East Eye, 28 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.middleeasteye.net/discover/turkey-syria-earthquake-mental-health-impact&quot;&gt;https://www.middleeasteye.net/discover/turkey-syria-earthquake-mental-health-impact&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Person, and Timour Azhari Humeyra Pamuk. “After Turkey’s Earthquake, a Grave Mental Health Toll Looms.” Reuters, Thomson Reuters, 27 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/after-turkeys-earthquake-grave-mental-health-toll-looms-2023-02-27/&quot;&gt;https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/after-turkeys-earthquake-grave-mental-health-toll-looms-2023-02-27/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Harriet Lai&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harriet Lai</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">On February 6, 2023, a catastrophic earthquake changed the lives of millions of people in Turkey and Syria. This earthquake resulted in a death toll of more than 50,000 people, while leaving millions more people homeless. This 7.8 magnitude earthquake will not only lead to years of rebuilding, but also mental health problems for those who survived. Mental health issues are prevalent all around the world. In America, nearly 20% of all adults suffer some form of mental illness with 10 million of them suffering severe mental illness. When someone experiences trauma, they become more vulnerable to developing mental illnesses, making the issue even more prevalent A study on the 2010 Canterbury earthquake in New Zealand found that there was an association between increased rates of disorder and increased rates of exposure to trauma. Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), anxiety levels, nicotine addiction, and overall disorders all increased for survivors after the earthquake, and they could last for up to seven years after the earthquake. The severity of the illness also results from many factors. For example, people who live in poorer regions of a city are more likely to have trauma because the poorer infrastructure leads to more destruction. This means that there are more people in the area who are suffering and dying, contributing to that trauma. This is especially true in many regions in Turkey and Syria, where they do not have the buildings like Japan that are designed to withstand strong earthquakes as a result of all the time and money spent to ensure their buildings can be used again after an earthquake.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Turkey-Syria%20Earthquake%20and%20Its%20Impact%20on%20Mental%20Health.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Syrian Earthquake Exasperate Refugee Problem &amp;amp; History of Syrian Civil War</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Earthquake-Exasperate-Refugee-Problem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Syrian Earthquake Exasperate Refugee Problem &amp; History of Syrian Civil War" /><published>2023-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Earthquake-Exasperate-Refugee-Problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Earthquake-Exasperate-Refugee-Problem/">&lt;p&gt;“They’re saying that the west is prioritizing politics over the humanitarian situation, but that’s not true. To give priority to one over the other both situations - the humanitarian and the political - have to exist. In the west, only the political situation exists, not the humanitarian. The politicization of the situation - that’s normal; but the humanitarian situation don’t exist, either today or in the past,” Syrian president Bashar Al-Assad said to interviewers. Destroyed buildings can be seen in the background of the clip. - Sky News UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When two consecutive earthquakes struck Turkey and northern Syria, twenty thousand people were buried alive while hundreds of thousands of others were displaced from their homes. Many Syrians still seek asylum from neighboring countries, primarily Turkey, which worsened the already tense debate among EU members on refugee issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the earthquake hit, leaders of the EU gathered to implement stricter border control that would limit irregular migration. They discussed surveillance, asylum registration, and return measures. However, the advent of the earthquake caused an influx of refugees from Syria and Turkey to EU countries. Mixed with other conflicts such as the Ukrainian war displacing 8 million people, the EU’s migration policies are clearly unenthusiastic and cautious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the refugee problem is not a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, what began as teens protesting against the brutal reign of the Al-Assad regime in Syria became a full-scale civil war as civilians mobilized in retaliation. The rebels hoped to establish a new rule away from the oppressive Assad family rule. In response, the Syrian army mobilized and struck cities with the most rebel activity. In the early stages, the army laid siege to Dereaa, the first of many sieges that would kill thousands of civilians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rebel army lacked professional organization, and the Syrian National Coalition eventually emerged as the representative of Syrians. Yet the coalition’s inefficiency, mixed with the government intentionally freeing extremist religious prisoners, gave rise to Al-Qaeda and the Islamic state. These religious extremist groups proved efficient in combat against the government regime, although their motivation was to capitalize on the chaos of the civil war, establish a footing in Syria, and create a new nation under the Sunni doctrine. The Assad regime and its biggest opposition, the Islamic State, both target civilians in the war, killing thousands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diplomacy of the war was complicated, as many attempted political resolutions of the conflict failed. This created a stalemate as many countries tried to provide military and humanitarian assistance instead. The US, UK, and France have aided the Syrian resistance force in training and medical provision, while Russia and Iran provided the Syrian government with soldiers. But in 2020, Russia closed three of the four routes used for the delivery of humanitarian aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early 2020 saw the official ceasefire, though the destruction of the war forced over 13.5 million Syrians from their homes and 6.8 million refugees hosted in over 100 countries. The war also crippled the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earthquake of February 2023 showed us the fragility of a nation marred by civil conflict, as the quakes destroyed more buildings in Syria and worsened the pre-existing economic, social, and political issues in Syria. In many ways, the Earthquake in Syria is an extension of the crisis of the civil war. President Assad’s comments are extreme in dismissing completely the presence of humanitarian aid from EU countries, and it also reveals hidden intentions and alliances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Cullinan, Kerry. “As Earthquakes Hit Turkey and Syria, Who Extends Refugee Health Plan – Undertakes Traditional Medicine Policy.” Health Policy Watch, 6 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://healthpolicy-watch.news/as-earthquakes-hit-turkey-and-syria-who-extends-refugee-health-plan-undertakes-traditional-medicine-policy/&quot;&gt;https://healthpolicy-watch.news/as-earthquakes-hit-turkey-and-syria-who-extends-refugee-health-plan-undertakes-traditional-medicine-policy/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Laub, Zachary. “Syria’s War and the Descent into Horror.” Council on Foreign Relations, Council on Foreign Relations, 14 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/article/syrias-civil-war&quot;&gt;https://www.cfr.org/article/syrias-civil-war&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mathieson, Rosalind. “Quake Crisis to Sharpen Europe Migration Debate.” Bloomberg.com, Bloomberg, 9 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2023-02-09/quake-crisis-to-sharpen-europe-migration-debate-balance-of-power&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2023-02-09/quake-crisis-to-sharpen-europe-migration-debate-balance-of-power&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mullen, Jethro, and Brian Walker. “Syria’s Bashar Al-Assad: West Is to Blame for Refugee Crisis.” CNN, Cable News Network, 16 Sept. 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2015/09/16/middleeast/syria-al-assad-interview/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnn.com/2015/09/16/middleeast/syria-al-assad-interview/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Refugee Statistics.” USA for UNHCR, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unrefugees.org/refugee-facts/statistics/&quot;&gt;https://www.unrefugees.org/refugee-facts/statistics/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Stamatoukou, Eleni. “Eu Agrees Stricter Migration Measures after Quakes in Turkey, Syria.” Balkan Insight, 10 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://balkaninsight.com/2023/02/10/eu-agrees-stricter-migration-measures-after-quakes-in-turkey-syria/&quot;&gt;https://balkaninsight.com/2023/02/10/eu-agrees-stricter-migration-measures-after-quakes-in-turkey-syria/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Tokyay, Menekse. “Post-Quake Environment Could Fuel Anti-Immigrant Sentiment in Turkiye .” Arab News, Arabnews, 12 Feb. 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arabnews.com/node/2249781/middle-east&quot;&gt;https://www.arabnews.com/node/2249781/middle-east&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Brian Yu&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by Sophia Huang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">“They’re saying that the west is prioritizing politics over the humanitarian situation, but that’s not true. To give priority to one over the other both situations - the humanitarian and the political - have to exist. In the west, only the political situation exists, not the humanitarian. The politicization of the situation - that’s normal; but the humanitarian situation don’t exist, either today or in the past,” Syrian president Bashar Al-Assad said to interviewers. Destroyed buildings can be seen in the background of the clip. - Sky News UK</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/History%20of%20Syrian%20Civil%20War.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Safety Tips for Different Types of Natural Disasters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Natural-Disasters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Safety Tips for Different Types of Natural Disasters" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Natural-Disasters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Natural-Disasters/">&lt;p&gt;Threatening to strike at any place and time, an earthquake is a rapid shaking caused by the shifting of rocks underneath the earth’s surface. In order to prepare your home for such a phenomenon, fasten all bookcases and shelving to walls. Place large, heavy, and fragile objects on lower shelves. Know where the electricity, gas, and water switches and valves are so they can be shut off quickly. Once an earthquake starts, it is important that everyone knows how to react. Create, practice, and follow an emergency plan that includes safe places where everyone can take cover, like a sturdy piece of furniture. If it starts while you are inside a car, pull over and stop, making sure to set the parking brake. Turn on the radio for emergency broadcast information as well. If outdoors, stay away from any buildings or tall trees and find an open area. In coastal areas, make sure to find higher ground as a tsunami could pose threats to your home and family. Finally, if inside, avoid running outside and don’t stand under doorways. Drop to the ground, cover your head and neck, and hold onto something sturdy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a fire starts in one’s home, they may only have two minutes to gather their loved ones and escape. A fire is a natural disaster that can strike unexpectedly, which is why it is important to be prepared. Smoke alarms should be installed in every level of the home. These alarms must be tested once a month, because if they are not, the people of the household will not be alerted in the case of a fire . Additionally, every household must have an emergency escape plan. Even if the alarms work, residents may not survive the fire if they don’t designate a meeting place and don’t have knowledge of the safest way to evacuate. Not only should households be prepared for fires, but they should also take steps to prevent them. For example, smoking indoors was the leading cause of home fire deaths from 2014 to 2018. These statistics should convince smokers to avoid doing so while indoors. Furthermore, cooking with negligence poses a fire hazard. Be attentive,: stay close to the kitchen while food is cooking, and make sure flammable items are 3 feet away from the stovetop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fatalities can also occur because of human interaction with the environment. Lung cancer, respiratory infections, and heart disease: these are all diseases caused by air pollution. According to the World Health Organization, 2.4 million people die each year from air pollution. Human activity, especially in highly populated cities, is the major cause of this issue. Citizens should take steps to protect the environment and reverse these detrimental effects. For example, using less energy such as electricity and gasoline will directly help with the global problem of air pollution. Turning off the lights or shutting off the TV are simple habits that prove to be impactful. Some home appliances, like light bulbs and stoves, use more energy than others, so avoid energy-hungry appliances. Solar power is also an excellent way to reduce emissions, as solar panels don’t release greenhouse gasses. Even while on the road, drivers can reduce their carbon footprint by opting for climate-friendly electric cars and leaving. Additionally, children and teens can either take public transportation or carpool on the way to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though tragedy threatens to strike at any moment, we can take steps to prevent these deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Ducksters. “Environment for Kids: Air Pollution.” Ducksters, Technological Solutions, Inc. (TSI), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ducksters.com/science/environment/air_pollution.php&quot;&gt;https://www.ducksters.com/science/environment/air_pollution.php&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 10 March 2023 &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“California Air Resources Board.” Simple Solutions to Help Reduce Air Pollution | California Air Resources Board, 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ww2.arb.ca.gov/resources/fact-sheets/simple-solutions-help-reduce-air-pollution&quot;&gt;https://ww2.arb.ca.gov/resources/fact-sheets/simple-solutions-help-reduce-air-pollution&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 10 March 2023 &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Home Fire Safety.” Home Fire Prevention &amp;amp; Safety Tips | American Red Cross, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redcross.org/get-help/how-to-prepare-for-emergencies/types-of-emergencies/fire.html&quot;&gt;https://www.redcross.org/get-help/how-to-prepare-for-emergencies/types-of-emergencies/fire.html&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 10 March 2023 &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Vigderman, Aliza. “Fire Safety &amp;amp; Prevention Tips to Follow in 2023.” Security.org, 29 Nov. 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.security.org/home-security-systems/fire-safety-tips/&quot;&gt;https://www.security.org/home-security-systems/fire-safety-tips/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 10 March 2023&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Earthquakes.” Earthquakes | Ready.gov, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ready.gov/earthquakes&quot;&gt;https://www.ready.gov/earthquakes&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 10 March 2023&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Earthquake Safety Tips.” Mass.gov, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mass.gov/info-details/earthquake-safety-tips&quot;&gt;https://www.mass.gov/info-details/earthquake-safety-tips&lt;/a&gt;.
Accessed 10 March 2023.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Aava Ghorbanian&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aava Ghorbanian</name></author><summary type="html">Threatening to strike at any place and time, an earthquake is a rapid shaking caused by the shifting of rocks underneath the earth’s surface. In order to prepare your home for such a phenomenon, fasten all bookcases and shelving to walls. Place large, heavy, and fragile objects on lower shelves. Know where the electricity, gas, and water switches and valves are so they can be shut off quickly. Once an earthquake starts, it is important that everyone knows how to react. Create, practice, and follow an emergency plan that includes safe places where everyone can take cover, like a sturdy piece of furniture. If it starts while you are inside a car, pull over and stop, making sure to set the parking brake. Turn on the radio for emergency broadcast information as well. If outdoors, stay away from any buildings or tall trees and find an open area. In coastal areas, make sure to find higher ground as a tsunami could pose threats to your home and family. Finally, if inside, avoid running outside and don’t stand under doorways. Drop to the ground, cover your head and neck, and hold onto something sturdy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Safety%20tips%20for%20different%20types%20of%20natural%20disasters.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Global Cooling before Global Warming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Global-Cooling-before-Global-Warming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Global Cooling before Global Warming" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Global-Cooling-before-Global-Warming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Global-Cooling-before-Global-Warming/">&lt;p&gt;This recent cold weather over the West Coast has more disastrous impacts than one may think. Last week, on March 5th, Texas saw snow for the first time in years. California has been hit with a wave of cool weather, causing there to be snow on the Hollywood sign and hail in Newport Beach. This caused a flurry of road closures, as well as many floods and storms. Mudslides, fallen trees, and power outages are only some examples of the environmental destruction that this cold streak weather has caused. For one of the first times in 20 years, Los Angeles’ weather has stayed below 60 degrees for 8 consecutive days. Although this is a delight for skiers, it also indicates the presence of an environmental disaster. Currently, though weather forecasters predict a warming period that will follow the storms, Newport Beach and the Orange County area continue to see downpours, stormy weather, and constant frigid temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its regional impact, this cooling period may seem insignificant in the context of global events. Currently, global warming, the heating of the surface of the Earth from pollution, has become a more pressing issue in recent events. Some causes of global warming include greenhouse gas emissions and industrial processes that release air pollutants into the atmosphere. In current news, a company called Willow is causing much controversy. President Biden is in the process of signing a bill that would allow Willow to build three oil drilling sites in Alaska, which will inevitably worsen the pollution that causes global warming. Lawmakers are backing this project with the belief that it will create more employment opportunities, but environmental activists argue that the benefits are not worth the cost of the environment. Additionally, indigenous populations in Alaska worry that this project will infringe on their territory, as many large companies have done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before global warming occurs, scientists have predicted that the Earth will engage in a global cooling process. Historically, global cooling has occurred before major industrialization projects. In the 1970s, global cooling occurred before mass industrialization started global warming. This leads scientists to the question, was the Earth cooling down before it began to warm? The data from a study conducted by the University of Arizona goes to show that yes, the Earth was cooling. This is significant because if history repeats itself, this could impact our interpretation of the recent small-scale weather anomaly that is occurring on the West Coast. Although the colder than usual weather along the West Coast may not be an immediate cause of alarm, it reminds us that global warming is still a pressing concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basf.com/us/en/who-we-are/change-for-climate.html?at_medium=display&amp;amp;at_campaign=COM_BAW_US_EN_Climate-Protection_QEI_Google-Generic-Phrase-2022&amp;amp;at_creation=Search_Google_EN_Text-Ad_Generic-Climate-Protection&amp;amp;at_channel=Google&amp;amp;at_format=Text-Ad&amp;amp;at_variant=Climate-Protection_1000x100_EN-Climate-Protection&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiAx6ugBhCcARIsAGNmMbg0lCByARECWEColzYmrLhD9QobluXN7ASkK4ygoEWmQT49ZOoVdLoaAg_oEALw_wcB&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;&gt;https://www.basf.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2023-02-28/southern-california-winter-storm-los-angeles-long-cold-streak&quot;&gt;https://www.latimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/global-warming-vs-climate-change/#:~:text=Global%20warming%20is%20the%20long,gas%20levels%20in%20Earth's%20atmosphere.&quot;&gt;https://climate.nasa.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/07/politics/willow-project-alaska-oil-explained-climate/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnn.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.arizona.edu/story/global-warming-was-earth-cooling-down-or-heating&quot;&gt;https://news.arizona.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Raquel Rybakova&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raquel Rybakova</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">This recent cold weather over the West Coast has more disastrous impacts than one may think. Last week, on March 5th, Texas saw snow for the first time in years. California has been hit with a wave of cool weather, causing there to be snow on the Hollywood sign and hail in Newport Beach. This caused a flurry of road closures, as well as many floods and storms. Mudslides, fallen trees, and power outages are only some examples of the environmental destruction that this cold streak weather has caused. For one of the first times in 20 years, Los Angeles’ weather has stayed below 60 degrees for 8 consecutive days. Although this is a delight for skiers, it also indicates the presence of an environmental disaster. Currently, though weather forecasters predict a warming period that will follow the storms, Newport Beach and the Orange County area continue to see downpours, stormy weather, and constant frigid temperature.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Global%20Colling%20Before%20Global%20Warming.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Underneath the Blinding Lights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/star-wars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Underneath the Blinding Lights" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/star-wars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/star-wars/">&lt;p&gt;The crowd roars as the ball is jousted into the air. The cry of the stadium swings with the ball like a pendulum. At this moment, both sides of the stadium scream their war cries for blood and pain. None of them know of the blood and sweat laid underneath to fuel their dream. Qatar forced countless people to their deaths building their extravagant stadiums. According to Qatari officials, there were “between 400 and 500” deaths among workers at World Cup stadium construction sites. The workers shout for rights, help, and basic freedom all around Earth. Four hundred to five hundred construction worker deaths in Qatar while preparing for the 2022 FIFA World Cup have been widely reported and criticized. The country has faced criticism for inadequate working conditions and labor laws, with some workers facing exploitation, long hours, and hazardous working environments. According to human rights organizations, hundreds of workers have died while working on World Cup-related infrastructure projects. The Qatari government has made efforts to improve working conditions, but more needs to be done to ensure the safety and rights of all workers in the country. The international community, FIFA, and corporations with ties to World Cup projects have a responsibility to advocate for fair and safe working conditions in Qatar, as well as for all workers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Oneal Wang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Oneal Wang</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">The crowd roars as the ball is jousted into the air. The cry of the stadium swings with the ball like a pendulum. At this moment, both sides of the stadium scream their war cries for blood and pain. None of them know of the blood and sweat laid underneath to fuel their dream. Qatar forced countless people to their deaths building their extravagant stadiums. According to Qatari officials, there were “between 400 and 500” deaths among workers at World Cup stadium construction sites. The workers shout for rights, help, and basic freedom all around Earth. Four hundred to five hundred construction worker deaths in Qatar while preparing for the 2022 FIFA World Cup have been widely reported and criticized. The country has faced criticism for inadequate working conditions and labor laws, with some workers facing exploitation, long hours, and hazardous working environments. According to human rights organizations, hundreds of workers have died while working on World Cup-related infrastructure projects. The Qatari government has made efforts to improve working conditions, but more needs to be done to ensure the safety and rights of all workers in the country. The international community, FIFA, and corporations with ties to World Cup projects have a responsibility to advocate for fair and safe working conditions in Qatar, as well as for all workers around the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/workersrights.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrant Workers under the Extravaganza</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrant Workers under the Extravaganza" /><published>2023-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/migrant-workers/">&lt;p&gt;As one of the most important sporting events in the world, the FIFA World Cup in Qatar had over 5.4 billion viewers. Since the announcement of the Qatar World Cup in December 2010, construction and preparation commenced to make the first FIFA World Cup in the Middle East possible. Immigrants from India and Africa built stadiums, secured safety of the games, and provided service, acting as a crucial factor that allowed the World Cup to take place. A total of two million migrant workers helped to facilitate the process, but among them, over 6,500 people have died due to poor living and working conditions, highlighting the underlying problem behind the World Cup and exposing the larger topic of worker abuse. The FIFA World Cup was not the first example of abuse of migrant workers as the root of the problem can be traced back to the last century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A significant factor contributing to workers’ abuse in Qatar is the Kafala System, or the Sponsorship System. Originally adopted in the 1950s, this system legally binds foreign workers to their employers, leaving the workers prone to manipulation and without the ability to escape such abuse. While the system was originally created to enhance regulation between employers and migrant workers, this policy now only takes away migrant workers’ freedom and makes them dependent on their employers. For instance, employers were responsible for renewing migrant workers’ resident permits, which the workers themselves had no control over. However, when the permits failed to be renewed, the workers then became the victims that had to bear the consequences themselves. Furthermore, the employers also had the power to cancel workers’ permits, demonstrating the power disparity which dismisses the laborer’s human rights and causes the workers to be stuck in a cycle of abuse. Furthermore, other prohibitions such as passport confiscation prevent workers from leaving the country, adding onto the problem. The lack of labor unions and labor laws in the society also shows problematic judicial and legislative practices that are hostile to migrant workers. Collectively, the system in Qatar made the migrant workers prone to labor exploitation, leaving them vulnerable during the FIFA World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the construction of the stadiums, the two largest problems the workers faced were wage delay and injustice. Amnesty International revealed that 100 employees of Qatar Meta Coats were not paid any wages for as long as seven months. In response to this, FIFA stated that they were unaware of this issue, implying that they failed to take cases of human rights abuses linked to the World Cup seriously. Moreover, even when workers were paid wages, the amount they received was extremely minimal. Ironically, while Qatar had spent nearly $220 billion on new infrastructure for the World Cup, they had kept labor costs low for the migrant workers. In addition to low wages, migrant workers in Qatar received lack of proper recognition for their deaths, and the true causes of their deaths were hidden by the responsible committees. In fact, while there have been 37 deaths that were directly linked to construction of World Cup stadiums, 34 of them were classified as “non-work related”. In many other examples, the deaths were covered up as “natural death” in order to conceal the workers’ abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding this issue, ongoing protests and public reforms were also important in dictating the prospect of migrant workers’ future. In 2017, the Qatar government signed an agreement with the International Labor Organization (ILO) to prevent labor exploitation and adhere labor practices to the international standards. This marks a sign for positive change, but it will not be effective until it is properly enforced. However, in many cases, weak implementation limits the impact of beneficial legislation to the workers. For instance, the Workers’ Welfare Standards provides restrictions on worker abuse and was meant to protect the workers under abuse, nevertheless examples of exploitation remained prevalent. Targeting the sponsorship system, the country ended the exit permit requirement in 2018 and allowed the workers to have the freedom to leave. Overall, many advancements have been made to improve the workers’ access to justice, health and safety, and wages, but in order to maintain a positive trend, there needs to be increased monitoring and detection of abuse. It is necessary for companies to respect the human rights of all workers equally for the abuse of migrant workers to one day come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Sources: &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;26, December. “BeIN Sports Announces Record-Breaking Cumulative Viewership of 5.4 Billion for FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022TM.” BeIN SPORTS, 26 Dec. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beinsports.com/en/fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/news/bein-sports-announces-record-breaking-cumulat/2011581&quot;&gt;https://www.beinsports.com/en/fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/news/bein-sports-announces-record-breaking-cumulat/2011581&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Profile of the FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022™​.” FIFA Publications, &lt;a href=&quot;https://publications.fifa.com/en/sustainability-report/sustainability-at-the-fifa-world-cup/profile-of-the-fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/&quot;&gt;https://publications.fifa.com/en/sustainability-report/sustainability-at-the-fifa-world-cup/profile-of-the-fifa-world-cup-qatar-2022/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Reality Check: Migrant Workers’ Rights in Qatar.” Amnesty International, 20 Oct. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/campaigns/2019/02/reality-check-migrant-workers-rights-with-two-years-to-qatar-2022-world-cup/&quot;&gt;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/campaigns/2019/02/reality-check-migrant-workers-rights-with-two-years-to-qatar-2022-world-cup/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Revealed: 6,500 Migrant Workers Have Died in Qatar since World Cup Awarded.” The Guardian, Guardian News and Media, 23 Feb. 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/feb/23/revealed-migrant-worker-deaths-qatar-fifa-world-cup-2022&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/feb/23/revealed-migrant-worker-deaths-qatar-fifa-world-cup-2022&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“Op-Ed: The Kafala Sponsorship System Fuels Modern Day Slavery.” Ed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.bu.edu/pardeeatlas/opinions/op-ed-the-kafala-sponsorship-system-fuels-modern-day-slavery/#:~:text=The%20Kafala%20sponsorship%20was%20originally,boom%20in%20these%20growing%20nations&quot;&gt;https://sites.bu.edu/pardeeatlas/opinions/op-ed-the-kafala-sponsorship-system-fuels-modern-day-slavery&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Ward, Ian. “The Many, Many Controversies Surrounding the 2022 World Cup, Explained.” Vox, Vox, 19 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/world/23450515/world-cup-fifa-qatar-2022-controversy-scandals-explained&quot;&gt;https://www.vox.com/world/23450515/world-cup-fifa-qatar-2022-controversy-scandals-explained&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Annie Zhu&lt;br /&gt;
Edited by: Shiksha Anand&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Annie Zhu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">As one of the most important sporting events in the world, the FIFA World Cup in Qatar had over 5.4 billion viewers. Since the announcement of the Qatar World Cup in December 2010, construction and preparation commenced to make the first FIFA World Cup in the Middle East possible. Immigrants from India and Africa built stadiums, secured safety of the games, and provided service, acting as a crucial factor that allowed the World Cup to take place. A total of two million migrant workers helped to facilitate the process, but among them, over 6,500 people have died due to poor living and working conditions, highlighting the underlying problem behind the World Cup and exposing the larger topic of worker abuse. The FIFA World Cup was not the first example of abuse of migrant workers as the root of the problem can be traced back to the last century.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/abuse.jpeg" /></entry></feed>