<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-31T20:18:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Our Generation</title><subtitle>This is homepage for SHS Our Generation Club.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Gun Violence in Schools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-in-Schools/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gun Violence in Schools" /><published>2024-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-in-Schools</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-in-Schools/"><![CDATA[<p>According to statistical evidence gathered by Sandy Hook Promise, around 12  children die from gun violence everyday in America and 93% of school shooting cases were planned in advance. Moreover, around 20% of the firearm owners who have children confess that they have unlocked firearms at home(Azrael). These shocking data remind the public of the necessity to understand that the gun violence problem happens everyday in both higher or lower schools, threatening students’ lives.</p>

<p>Gun violence problems plague college campuses. One of the most deadly mass shooting cases in schools happened on April 16, 2007 in Virginia tech university. Seung-Hui Cho, a former student of Virginia Tech, killed 33 people on campus, including himself. Cho lived in South Korea when he was younger, and then moved to the United States with his family. He perceived the world differently than other people. According to Cho’s parents and psychiatrist, he was diagnosed with selective mutism and possible autism at a young age. He was extremely quiet in classes and did not establish any close bonds with any of his classmates or teachers. Once his teacher noticed Cho’s abnormal behaviors from the idolization of Eric Harris and Dylan Klebold, who committed the Columbine High School massacre in 1999, and to his school projects expressing his intentions to “repeat Columbine”. However, because of the negelection from the schools and the doctors later in his life, the catastrophic prediction became the truth. In Cho’s case, he was found to have mental issues at the beginning, yet what worsens the situation is the nonfeasance of those people around him. The 32 innocent lives might have been saved if any of Cho’s classmates, teachers, or psychiatrist realized the urgency of his situation and provided him support, or they recognized his behaviors as a threat to public safety and reported it to schools or police. Therefore, we all have the responsibility to pay attention to our surroundings and recognize others’ abnormal behaviors.</p>

<p>Besides college shooting cases, lower schools are also threatened by gun violence. On March 28, 2023, the Tennessee police department reported a mass shooting at a Christian school in Nashville. Contrary to what the public suspects, this mass shooting case took place in an elementary school instead of a college campus where school mass shootings normally happen. The shooter, Audrey Hale, a 28 years old alumna from the school, shot and killed three 9 year olds and three adults on the school campus. Later her parents admitted that Audrey legally purchased seven guns, and three of them were used on the day of the incident. Similar to Seung-Hui Cho in the previous case, Audrey Hale also appeared to have psychological issues and proposed her own versions of “Blueprint on destruction”, her journals that are not yet released due to the potential danger it could present to the public, on school shootings.</p>

<p>Comparing specifically Cho and Audrey’s gun violence cases, similarities arose from both cases. We can easily see that in both cases, the shooter, who were both former students of their target schools, both experienced some kind of psychological issues and have revealed their intention of performing a mass shooting a long time before the incident. Summarizing all former school shooting cases, the United States government published a booklet on “Protecting America’s Schools, A U.S Secret Service Analysis of Targeted School Violence” for future references. According to the booklet, a majority of attackers showed signs of psychological, behavioral, or developmental issues and approximately 50% had an interest in violent topics. Moreover, most shooters were stressed by relationships with peers or significant others, and almost all had experienced bullying by other students. Gun violences is preventable, as long as we pay attention to the signs it’s showing us. 
<a href="https://youtu.be/A8syQeFtBKc">(PSA)</a></p>

<p>In conclusion, in order to have self protection in front of gun violence, students should be able to identify potential gun violence around them through paying more attention to the surrounding and understanding perceptions of the shooters. However, for the purpose of preventing these gun violence cases from happening, institutes should take their responsibilities to protect the students and provide them with a safe and secure learning environment. Improvements such as setting up and training the teachers and the students with code red drills, installing bullet proof doors and windows if possible, and implementing a stricter security check in schools could significantly lower the risks of school shootings.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small>Azrael, Deborah, and Matthew Miller. “Firearm Storage in US Households With Children Findings From the 2021 National Firearm Survey.” Jama Network, 22 Feb. 2022, jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2789269.</small></p>

<p><small>Levenson, Eric, et al. “Nashville Private School Shooting Suspect Had Maps of Building and Scouted Possible Second Attack Location, Police Say.” CNN, Cable News Network, 28 Mar. 2023, www.cnn.com/2023/03/27/us/covenant-school-shooting-nashville-tennessee/index.html.
</small></p>

<p><small>“Protecting America’s Schools - United States Secret Service.” United States Secret Service, Department of Homeland Security UNITED STATES SECRET SERVICE, 2019, www.secretservice.gov/sites/default/files/2020-04/Protecting_Americas_Schools.pdf.
</small></p>

<p><small>“Virginia Tech Shooting.” History.com, A&amp;E Television Networks, www.history.com/this-day-in-history/massacre-at-virginia-tech-leaves-32-dead.
</small></p>

<p><small>“17 Facts about Gun Violence and School Shootings.” Sandy Hook Promise, 27 Apr. 2023, www.sandyhookpromise.org/blog/gun-violence/facts-about-gun-violence-and-school-shootings/.
</small></p>

<p>Written by Yusong Liang</p>

<p>Edited by Joyce Rizko</p>]]></content><author><name>Yusong Liang</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to statistical evidence gathered by Sandy Hook Promise, around 12 children die from gun violence everyday in America and 93% of school shooting cases were planned in advance. Moreover, around 20% of the firearm owners who have children confess that they have unlocked firearms at home(Azrael). These shocking data remind the public of the necessity to understand that the gun violence problem happens everyday in both higher or lower schools, threatening students’ lives.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunschools.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunschools.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gradual Uptick</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gradual-Uptick/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gradual Uptick" /><published>2024-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gradual-Uptick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gradual-Uptick/"><![CDATA[<p>Per Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, self-preservation lies near the bottom; demonstrating that humans yearn for safety above just about all else – especially through firearms. In 2022, 45% of households in the United States owned at least one gun; this number was last reached in 2012 after the 2011 Tucson Shooting. Due to wars and exposure to violence, many think safety means having the power to fight back. This belief causes a spike in gun sales after every shooting, and, consequently, a rise in the stocks of companies dealing in firearms.</p>

<p>2021 ended with an astounding 692 – the United States had suffered only 358 five years before. After noting the considerable increase of gun sales, the University of California Davis studied the sales numbers throughout the year. Researchers found that more people were buying firearms both within 30 days of a mass shooting and in December. Naturally, after a mass shooting, people get scared and think that owning a gun will protect them in case of future incidents and level the playing field. As for the trend in December, there exists two main explanations. Firstly, some may buy guns as gifts. However, the more major contributor would be the legislative gun laws that go in effect every year on January 1. Every mass shooting motivates the government to create more laws, and, in doing so, people invest in firearms at the end of year in case of bans. All of these reasons accumulate, and, as of 2020, the state of California measured 1.16 million gun sales for the year – and the number continues to rise. Additionally, people do not just want guns anymore. Requests for bump stocks – a piece that enhances firing speed – rose ever since a shooting in Las Vegas. The dramatic increase in gun sales after every mass shooting means not only an increase of firearms in circulation, but also higher stocks for those selling these items.</p>

<p>Openly-traded firearm companies gain incredible amounts of money after every mass shooting. Both bigger ones, like Sturm, Ruger, &amp; Co. (commonly known as Ruger), and smaller ones, like Smith &amp; Wesson, all follow the same trend. Within one day of a shooting, they will peak and trade at a few dollars higher. Then, they will hover at a dollar or so less than the peak. Firearms company stocks have grown exponentially over the past few years, and citizens can only expect more growth as shootings continue.</p>

<p>Firearm companies have gained exorbitant amounts of money as people buy more guns post-shootings. With the growing and constant fear of a shooter, whether that be at school or the park, citizens feel the need to protect themselves. The growing distrust in the police force only adds to this. People feel the need to turn to the cause of their worries in order to live their life with some feeling of comfort and security. Should mass shootings die down, this might mean a disastrous fate for firearm companies.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small>Luscombe, Belinda. “Mass Shootings Are a Crisis. So Why Are Gunmakers Stocks Rising?” Time, 26 May 2021, https://time.com/6185520/mass-shootings-gunmakers/. Accessed 19 April 2023.</small></p>

<p><small>“Percentage of Households in the United States Owning a Firearm.” Statista, 2022, https://www.s tatista.com/statistics/249740/percentage-of-households-in-the-united-states-owning-a-firearm/. Accessed 19 April 2023. </small></p>

<p>Written by Joyce Rizko</p>]]></content><author><name>Joyce Rizko</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Per Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, self-preservation lies near the bottom; demonstrating that humans yearn for safety above just about all else – especially through firearms. In 2022, 45% of households in the United States owned at least one gun; this number was last reached in 2012 after the 2011 Tucson Shooting. Due to wars and exposure to violence, many think safety means having the power to fight back. This belief causes a spike in gun sales after every shooting, and, consequently, a rise in the stocks of companies dealing in firearms.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunup.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunup.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">At the Intersection of Film and Our Prison System</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Film/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At the Intersection of Film and Our Prison System" /><published>2024-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gun-Film</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Film/"><![CDATA[<p>500 percent. That’s the growth of our prison population since 1970, says American Civil Liberties Union; it also listed fractions - one in three, one in six, and one in seventeen - separately corresponding to the odds of black, latino, and white boys and their odds of any type of imprisonment in their lifetime. Obviously, our prisons aren’t just growing indiscriminately. So what does that mean for a society obsessed with crime and (unequal) punishment?</p>

<p>This article sought to link popular culture with basic data to help inform a general knowledge of the cause and effects of Modern Mass Incarceration.</p>

<p>Our first stop was in the beginning of the 70s, where president Nixon led the United States on a series of policies to combat illegal drug production, distribution and consumption which he later coined the “War on Drugs”. The policy is now worldwide, but for the United States, this meant longer sentences and stricter sentencing standards. You might know Scarface, the movie that tells of ambition turned vice, following the story of Tony Montana, a Cuban immigrant turned drug lord. This story is very much set in its milieu of the 1980s, now 10 years from the beginning of the on-going war on drugs. The movie itself not only offered perspective into the minds twisted by the excess of ambition and materialism, but also sets an accurate (in spirit) depiction of the crime scene involving drug importation.</p>

<p>With billions invested into the construction of new prisons and an unprecedented rising number of convicts coupled with inadequate funding for reintegrating ex-criminals into society, any period of life behind bars can feel like a life-sentence. Truly, the emphasis on punishment over correction in our prison systems is the biggest tragedy, one that left many people behind, with no real prospect of catching up.</p>

<p>Our cultural notion of prison escape then, is understandably pessimistic and necessarily harsh. Compared to Escape from Alcatraz, a 1979 prison escape film which became the 15th highest grossing film of that year, the 1994 film Shawshank Redemption is a box office flop, with negative initial critical response. The film release coincides with the height of “tough on crime” rhetoric, of which none other than our president Joe Biden is a part of. But subsequent generations have taken Shawshank to the highest prestige due to its moving story and its criticism of the social condition - the institutionalization of criminals, the notion that criminals, either due to long sentences or trauma, became better acclimated to the prison rule of power and it’s hierarchies than those of free society. Abuses in criminal labor are also prevalent in this film, which mirrors reality also, where criminals are put to work for no pay. Sounds familiar? Hence some critics of the prison system linking prison labor to slavery.</p>

<p>The Shawshank Redemption serves as an example of how films can reflect a truth despite its fictionality. But most importantly, after 50 years of expanding prisons, I think it’s time to invest also in the rehabilitation and reintegration of criminals. Once you get behind, you stay behind.</p>

<p>Written by Brian Yu</p>]]></content><author><name>Brian Yu</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[500 percent. That’s the growth of our prison population since 1970, says American Civil Liberties Union; it also listed fractions - one in three, one in six, and one in seventeen - separately corresponding to the odds of black, latino, and white boys and their odds of any type of imprisonment in their lifetime. Obviously, our prisons aren’t just growing indiscriminately. So what does that mean for a society obsessed with crime and (unequal) punishment?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunmassincarc.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunmassincarc.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Shot on Mental Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Mental-Health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Shot on Mental Health" /><published>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gun-Mental-Health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Mental-Health/"><![CDATA[<p>In the United States, the incidence of gun violence has increased to 43,000 deaths every year, an increase of more than 10,000 deaths as compared to a decade ago. This increase causes a pervasive feeling of insecurity and hypervigilance in people, leading to mental health challenges. Examples of improper gun use include mass shootings, gang violence, and police shootings, which all take a toll on the mental health of victims and witnesses. The trauma, fear, and grief associated with gun violence can lead to a range of mental health issues, such as depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), and substance abuse. In particular, those illnesses cause people to remain vulnerable to trauma for years and damage their nervous systems.</p>

<p>The impact of gun violence on the nervous system can be severe and long-lasting. The sudden and traumatic nature of gun violence can trigger the release of stress hormones such as cortisol and adrenaline, which can cause significant changes in the brain and nervous system. These changes result in a range of physical and psychological symptoms, including increased heart rate, rapid breathing, hypervigilance, and other symptoms of PTSD. According to CWLA, children who experience gun violence are exposed to negative psychological effects, “including anger, withdrawal, post traumatic stress, and desensitization to violence” (Garbarino et al., 2002). Exposure to gun violence leads to changes in the structure and function of the brain, particularly in areas responsible for emotional regulation and cognitive processing. Therefore, victims are subject to mood swings and health issues such as depression and anxiety.</p>

<p>In addition, gun violence disproportionately affects certain groups of people, including minorities and low income individuals. For people with lower socioeconomic status, they often live in areas where gun violence occurs more commonly, thus being exposed to more fatal and nonfatal shootings. Furthermore, people who live in neighborhoods with high rates of gun violence are more likely to experience chronic stress, causing an increase in allostatic load, damaging the immune system and disrupting the menstrual cycle. Moreover, certain demographic groups, such as children and women, are at a higher risk of gun violence, making them more vulnerable targets of mental disorders.</p>

<p>Lastly, not only does gun violence cause mental illnesses in victims, it also stigmatizes the people with mental illnesses and intensifies social tension. In the aftermath of a mass shooting or other violent incident involving firearms, people often blame the perpetrator’s mental illness as the cause of the violence. This blame can lead to stigmatization and discrimination against people with mental illnesses, causing unfair social exclusion and reduced access to healthcare services. For example, the National Rifle Association lays the blame of mass shootings on people with mental illnesses, while in reality such illnesses are not a reliable predictor of violence.</p>

<p>Overall, gun violence has a significant impact on mental health, which can lead to long-lasting physical and psychological symptoms. Individuals who are exposed to gun violence are at a higher risk of developing PTSD, anxiety, and depression. Moreover, gun violence disproportionately affects minorities, people with lower socioeconomic status, and those who have mental illnesses. Therefore, it is important to correctly analyze the nature of gun violence and promote social inclusion and acceptance for those with mental illnesses.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small>“Statistics.” Giffords, 4 Apr. 2023, https://giffords.org/lawcenter/gun-violence-statistics/. </small></p>

<p><small>admin, About the Author: “The Impact of Gun Violence on Children, Families, &amp; Communities.” CWLA, https://www.cwla.org/the-impact-of-gun-violence-on-children-families-communities/. 
</small></p>

<p><small>Melinda Smith, M.A. “Effects of Gun Violence on Mental Health.” HelpGuide.org, 28 Feb. 2023, https://www.helpguide.org/articles/ptsd-trauma/effects-of-gun-violence-on-mental-health.htm. 
</small></p>

<p><small>Swanson, Jeffrey W, et al. “Mental Illness and Reduction of Gun Violence and Suicide: Bringing Epidemiologic Research to Policy.” Annals of Epidemiology, U.S. National Library of Medicine, May 2015, https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4211925/.
 </small></p>

<p>Written by Annie Zhu</p>]]></content><author><name>Annie Zhu</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the United States, the incidence of gun violence has increased to 43,000 deaths every year, an increase of more than 10,000 deaths as compared to a decade ago. This increase causes a pervasive feeling of insecurity and hypervigilance in people, leading to mental health challenges. Examples of improper gun use include mass shootings, gang violence, and police shootings, which all take a toll on the mental health of victims and witnesses. The trauma, fear, and grief associated with gun violence can lead to a range of mental health issues, such as depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), and substance abuse. In particular, those illnesses cause people to remain vulnerable to trauma for years and damage their nervous systems.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunhealth.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunhealth.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comparing Gun Laws in Foreign Countries to the United States</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-Laws/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparing Gun Laws in Foreign Countries to the United States" /><published>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Comparing-Laws</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-Laws/"><![CDATA[<p>Gun laws are a hotly debated topic around the world, with many countries implementing strict regulations on firearms in order to reduce the incidence of gun-related crime. The United States, however, has historically taken a more liberal approach to gun ownership, with many individuals advocating for their right to bear arms. In this article, we will compare and contrast gun laws in other countries with those in the United States. According to the Gun Violence Archive, there were 43,559 incidents of gun violence in the United States in 2021, resulting in 11,347 deaths and 23,129 injuries. In contrast, countries with stricter gun laws such as Canada and Japan have significantly lower rates of gun violence. Canada had 223 gun-related deaths in 2019, while Japan had only six.</p>

<p>One of the main differences between gun laws in the United States and other countries is the ease with which individuals can obtain firearms. In the United States, there is no federal law requiring background checks on all gun sales, and in many states, individuals can purchase guns at gun shows without any background checks at all. In contrast, countries such as Canada and Australia require background checks on all gun purchases, and in many cases, individuals must demonstrate a legitimate reason for owning a firearm. Another significant difference is the types of firearms that are legal to own. In the United States, there are few restrictions on the types of guns that individuals can own, with some states allowing the ownership of automatic weapons and high-capacity magazines. In contrast, countries such as Japan and the United Kingdom have strict laws prohibiting the ownership of handguns and assault rifles. There is also a difference in the training required to obtain a gun license. In many countries, such as Canada and Australia, individuals must complete a safety course and demonstrate proficiency in handling firearms before they are allowed to purchase a gun. In the United States, there is no such requirement, and many individuals can purchase firearms without any training at all. Finally, there is a difference in the way gun ownership is viewed in different countries. In the United States, there is a strong cultural attachment to the right to bear arms, with many individuals viewing gun ownership as a fundamental right. In contrast, many countries view gun ownership as a privilege that must be earned and regulated.</p>

<p>In conclusion, there are significant differences in gun laws between the United States and other countries. While the United States takes a more liberal approach to gun ownership, with fewer restrictions on the types of guns that individuals can own and less regulation around the purchase and training required to obtain a gun license, countries with stricter gun laws such as Canada and Japan have significantly lower rates of gun violence. It is clear that the issue of gun control is complex and multifaceted, and will continue to be a topic of debate for years to come.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small>
<small>Pew Research Center: “Key Facts About Americans and Guns.” Pew Research Center, 13 Sept. 2021, www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2021/09/13/key-facts-about-americans-and-guns/. </small>
<small>Gun Violence Archive. www.gunviolencearchive.org. </small>
<small>The Trace: “Gun Violence Deaths Statistics in America.” The Trace, 2022, www.thetrace.org/2022/12/gun-violence-deaths-statistics-america/. </small></p>

<p>Written by Sophia Huang</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Huang</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gun laws are a hotly debated topic around the world, with many countries implementing strict regulations on firearms in order to reduce the incidence of gun-related crime. The United States, however, has historically taken a more liberal approach to gun ownership, with many individuals advocating for their right to bear arms. In this article, we will compare and contrast gun laws in other countries with those in the United States. According to the Gun Violence Archive, there were 43,559 incidents of gun violence in the United States in 2021, resulting in 11,347 deaths and 23,129 injuries. In contrast, countries with stricter gun laws such as Canada and Japan have significantly lower rates of gun violence. Canada had 223 gun-related deaths in 2019, while Japan had only six.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunschools.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunschools.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gun violence in the U.S.: By the numbers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-Numbers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gun violence in the U.S.: By the numbers" /><published>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-Numbers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gun-Violence-Numbers/"><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1G2NJMRcPhV1cUfJxzso73HWW_oKL75o_/preview" height="100%" width="100%" frameborder="2" scrolling="auto"></iframe>

<p>Written by Sophia Zhou</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Zhou</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/guninfo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/guninfo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Firing Blasters in Cold Blood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Star-Wars-Guns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firing Blasters in Cold Blood" /><published>2024-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Star-Wars-Guns</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Star-Wars-Guns/"><![CDATA[<p>Since its debut in 1977, Star Wars has captivated audiences around the world with its advanced technology, unique characters, and unforgettable one-liners. But even as Anakin Skywalker wrestles with Count Dooku over two lightsabers and Luke Skywalker fire the torpedo that destroyed a whole planet, the work (or rather bloodshed) inflicted by blasters remains inconspicuous. In the Star Wars universe, blasters are fictional energy-based weapons powered by an energy cell or power pack. When the trigger is pulled, blasters generate and propel superheated plasma or energy particles from a barrel or emitter as bolts of energy that burn a hole through their victims and cauterize their organs. Despite orchestrating the rise of Star Wars, blasters evolved over time to show the complexity of major protagonists murdering in cold blood on their journey for “the greater good”.</p>

<p>In the original 1977 release of Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope, wisecracking smuggler Han Solo, portrayed by Harrison Ford, finds himself cornered by Greedo, a Rodian bounty hunter commissioned by crime lord Jabba the Hutt seeking to collect a debt. In the original theatrical release, Han shoots Greedo under the table first, quickly dispatching Greedo and narrowly escaping danger. However, in subsequent re-releases and blue-ray editions of the film, the scene was altered to show Greedo shooting first, with Han narrowly dodging the shot and then firing in self-defense. Inspired by the real-life counterpart Mauser C96, Han Solo’s blaster pistol DL-44 pistol has helped Han escape the shadiest situations. However, this scene has sparked some controversy. On one hand, people wanted to see the ruthless side of Han Solo–a smuggler who only fends for himself which helps pave the way for his redemption. However, others argued for the inner character and morale of Han Solo, with Goerge Lucas eventually commenting that he “never designed Han to be a ruthless killer”. If Han shot first, not only will this lower his reputation among smugglers and possibly the rebel alliance, his low credibility will affect his future bounty runs. Meanwhile, if Greedo shot first, the event can be interpreted as Han’s quick reactions along with the greed of the Hutt Cartel. Regardless, firing any blaster in this context vilifies the perpetrator and brings a menacing connotation to firearms.</p>

<p>In season 2 of The Mandalorian, Mayfeld, a former Imperial sharpshooter, is forced to confront his past and face the officer responsible for his unit’s deaths. The officer, seemingly unrepentant, makes condescending remarks about the deaths, triggering Mayfeld’s rage. In a moment of catharsis, Mayfeld shoots the officer, showing that his allegiances lie with his own moral compass rather than with the Empire or even the rebellion. Wielding the Rodian DT-12, Mayfeld demonstrates the significance of a blaster shot and the transformation of themes in Star Wars. Much like Han Solo, Mayfeld is the hero of the segment and sets off a chain of events that eventually leads to the downfall of the empire, glorifying his use of gun violence. Unlike Han Solo, however, Mayfel is meant to be an antihero who serves his morals instead of a greater cause. However, this reckless act also jeopardizes the mission, forcing the Mandalorian to draw weapons and fight off overwhelming imperial forces. Even if an officer is guilty of reckless endangerment, U.S. laws indicate it is usually not in the hand of the victim to determine their survival. The show creates tension by showing the similarities between the imperial officer and Mayfeld, as both shared the same goal of unifying the galaxy yet both used different means to achieve it. The officer’s condescending tone highlights the possibility of Mayfeld’s greed for personal satisfaction for revenge and popularity over the greater good. At the end of the day, Mayfeld’s blaster silences suspicions of his allegiance and draws an ironic similarity between him and the imperials.</p>

<p>In the Disney+ TV show Andor, Cassian Andor was threatened by two inebriated off-duty imperial officers. Playing off of their gullibility, Cassian Andor killed an officer by snapping his neck to the ground. With tears streaming down his face, the author begged to join his partner and Andor executed him without hesitation. Wielding the K-16 Bryar Pistol, Andor is a long way off from his patriotic self in Rogue One. A smuggler by trade and a ruthless killer at best, Cassian Andor was just a mercenary making his way to the galaxy in pursuit of imperial credits. Unlike the other protagonists, Cassian Andor did not trust in any cause, believing all of them to be corrupt beyond saving. The show clearly moves away from traditional values of the significance of blasters as Andor’s willingness to kill warped the image of a righteous hero. Despite recognizing the officers under the influence of alcohol, Andor’s disdain for an unbalanced society questions his ethical implications in the first episode of the show, setting up a character arc that redeems Andor from a cruel mercenary to a reactionary rebel.</p>

<p>The violence of these three shots is underestimated, especially in the context of such a large franchise. However, Cassian Andor’s survival ultimately led to Rogue One and the survival of the rebel fleet, encouraging Han Solo’s rescue, and later Mayfeld’s assistance to hunt down imperial remnants. If all these events are interconnected and eventually led to 3 major wars in Star Wars, the franchise clearly outlines the lasting impact of gun violence. As the use of a gun led to the assassination of Archduke Ferdinand and the conflict of 2 world wars, gun control becomes increasingly important as the tension between countries today becomes even tighter.</p>

<p>Written by Oneal Wang</p>]]></content><author><name>Oneal Wang</name></author><category term="Gun Violence" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since its debut in 1977, Star Wars has captivated audiences around the world with its advanced technology, unique characters, and unforgettable one-liners. But even as Anakin Skywalker wrestles with Count Dooku over two lightsabers and Luke Skywalker fire the torpedo that destroyed a whole planet, the work (or rather bloodshed) inflicted by blasters remains inconspicuous. In the Star Wars universe, blasters are fictional energy-based weapons powered by an energy cell or power pack. When the trigger is pulled, blasters generate and propel superheated plasma or energy particles from a barrel or emitter as bolts of energy that burn a hole through their victims and cauterize their organs. Despite orchestrating the rise of Star Wars, blasters evolved over time to show the complexity of major protagonists murdering in cold blood on their journey for “the greater good”.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunstarwars.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gunstarwars.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/editor-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2023-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-editor-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/editor-words/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-kahramanmaras-earthquake">The Kahramanmaras Earthquake</h1>

<p>by Annie Zhu</p>

<p>On February 6th, 2023, two devastating earthquakes struck Turkey at its Syrian border. Following the first magnitude 7.8 earthquake, another magnitude 7.5 earthquake hit nine hours later. Thousands of people were killed and billions of dollars were lost from physical damage. The state authorities urgently declared a level 4 emergency and called for international assistance while the death toll climbed rapidly. To date, more than 9.1 million people have been affected, and more than 45,000 people were killed in this incident. By March 1, 2023, more than 11,000 aftershocks in the region have also added to the devastation. This earthquake is one of the largest in Turkey’s history, along with the 1668 North Anatolia earthquake and the 1939 Erzincan earthquake. One thing is certain – the destructive consequences of the event will remain for years to come.</p>

<p>The impact of the Kahramanmaras earthquake has had severe negative effects on physical and mental health of the residents in Turkey and Syria. Since the quake on February 6th, 1.9 million people have relocated and now live in temporary shelters after the disaster destroyed their houses. These poor living conditions make the survivors susceptible to health issues. Physical effects aside, the experience has led people to develop trauma and increased risk for chronic anxiety and depression. For instance, the survivors may develop Survivor’s Guilt as they believe that they have done something wrong when others have passed away in the tragic event. Furthermore, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake directly damaged $34.2 billion worth of buildings and facilities in Türkiye and Syria. This also exposed the design problems in buildings that were vulnerable to strong earthquakes, leading to more destruction due to anthropogenic factors. Ultimately, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake contributed to a large humanitarian crisis and caused economic problems that are affecting the lives of millions of people.</p>

<p>In response to the Kahramanmaras Earthquake, countries around the world have offered humanitarian support to relieve the level of destruction. For example, the United Nations have offered multiple cross-border aid operations to deliver supplies. The Bab Al-Hawa, Bab Al-Salam, and Al-Ra’ee have all been open for UN aid delivery, and by March 4th, 583 trucks with aid have crossed into Northwest Syria to provide assistance. However, according to an IFRC market assessment, hot meals, hygiene items, winter clothes, and many more critical necessities are still desperately needed in the affected areas.</p>

<p>Overall, being one of the worst earthquakes in recent years, the Kahramanmaras Earthquake has transformed the lives of many and is continuously affecting more. Similar to many other large-scale earthquakes in history, it destroyed local communities, the economy, and killed thousands of people. In addition to learning the details about how this earthquake has affected Türkiye and Syria and how the United States plays a role in this event, this issue also introduces past earthquakes that have heavily injured communities around the world. By learning about the history of earthquakes and juxtaposing different earthquakes for comparison, we will discuss the multifaceted impact of natural disasters in a comprehensive manner. From the effect on people’s mental health to global climate change, understanding the context beyond the Kahramanmaras Earthquake is essential for teenagers to provide better assistance.</p>

<h1 id="letter-from-the-editors-in-chief">Letter from the Editors in Chief</h1>

<p>Hello, we’re the Editors in Chief of Our Gen! Thank you for reading the March 2023 issue of Our Gen. Our goal for our club is to connect the teenagers in our current digital age to major current issues to help us further understand and care about the world around us. As writers, artists, and editors, our team has delved into current issues, connecting them back to our lives. Understanding earthquakes in Turkey is extremely important, and so is understanding how the natural fundamental environmental issue is affecting the entire world, including our homes. For example, California fault lines provide a dangerous possibility for earthquakes up to a magnitude of eight. In cases such as this, we believe that it is important to educate teenagers about these natural disasters so we can better protect ourselves and perhaps, one day, to be able to protect the human race from those deadly disasters.</p>

<p>We want to thank our amazing team for their hard work on this issue, our advisor Mrs. Chung for her constant support, and a special thank you to Ms.Tekin for inspiring us to take action and to influence others regarding the Turkey earthquakes. Our Generation reminds us how closely connected people are, and how even a small positive remark can leave a huge trace in someone’s lives.</p>

<p>With this, we hope our readers will take away the importance of understanding our world. Our Generation creates a platform for teenagers to utilize their voices and actions. Even more so, we would like to encourage and empower young adults to become agents of change and to make those positive impacts for our society. We, young adults, can shape the future. We are the future.</p>

<p>Sincerely,<br />
Chanah Y. &amp; Melody Y.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small><a href="https://disasterphilanthropy.org/disasters/2023-turkey-syria-earthquake/">2023 Turkey-Syria Earthquake - Center for Disaster Philanthropy</a></small></p>

<p><small><a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/turkiye/turkiye-2023-earthquakes-situation-report-no-6-3-march-2023">Türkiye: 2023 Earthquakes Situation Report No. 6, As of 3 March 2023</a></small></p>

<p><small><a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/survivors-of-deadly-earthquakes-must-deal-with-lasting-trauma/">Survivors of Deadly Earthquakes Must Deal with Lasting Trauma - Scientific American</a></small></p>

<p>Written by Annie Zhu</p>]]></content><author><name>Chanah Yin, Melody Yu</name></author><category term="Earthquakes in Turkey/Environmental Issues" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Kahramanmaras Earthquake]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/earthintro.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/earthintro.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of Earthquakes Around the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/History-of-Earthquake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of Earthquakes Around the World" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-History-of-Earthquake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/History-of-Earthquake/"><![CDATA[<p>Small earthquakes are quite common worldwide; a million or so happen each year. However, certain places are more susceptible to earthquakes due to their location near the seven major tectonic plates. As countries in those areas have continued to develop, new technologies lessen the damage and give citizens earthquake warnings, lowering mortality rates. So although high-magnitude earthquakes remain dangerous, the amount of damage they inflict is dependent on access to technologies to prevent earthquakes and governmental measures taken towards minimizing the dame of earthquakes. This is shown through the comparison of Japan and Haiti.</p>

<p>In 2010, Haiti experienced a magnitude 7.0 earthquake that killed around 222,570 people. According to the Earthquake Magnitude Scale, an earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 is considered a major earthquake but is not at the magnitude of other very destructive earthquakes. Still, the Haitian Earthquake had one of the highest death tolls from any earthquake in the 21st century. One of the reasons for this tragedy is the disorganization and lack of standardization in buildings in Haiti. When the 2010 earthquake hit, there was no early warning for its citizens. Also, there is no “national building code” enforced by the government, says Fouche, a Haitian earthquake engineer. The economic state in Haiti also played a role in why this earthquake was so deadly. Most people cannot afford newer technology developed to help lessen the impact of earthquakes, like shock absorption in buildings.</p>

<p>In Japan, because of its economic wealth, there are now buildings that have been designed with base isolators that allow a building to move from side to side while remaining standing during an earthquake. The government also has earthquake-resistant standards for new buildings and an early warning system to notify the citizens when there is an earthquake. A combination of effective warning and new technology is why when a 9.1 earthquake then tsunami happened in Japan, there were 11 times fewer deaths, even though the earthquake in Japan had a much high magnitude. These advancements have caused earthquakes in Japan to have fairly low mortality rates in recent years but have also helped prevent the amount of property damage from earthquakes.</p>

<p>Overall, earthquake magnitude, economic wealth, and government stability all contribute to the amount of damage that such a natural disaster will inflict upon a country. As the methods for earthquake damage control develop and become accessible, we hope all countries at risk of earthquakes will eventually be able to protect all of their citizens.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small>Joyce, Christopher. “Haiti’s Buildings Weren’t Fit to Withstand Quakes.” NPR, NPR, 14 Jan. 2010, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2010/01/14/122547242/haitis-buildings-werent-fit-to-withstand-quakes.">https://www.npr.org/2010/01/14/122547242/haitis-buildings-werent-fit-to-withstand-quakes</a>. </small></p>

<p><small>Fuller, Thomas, et al. “Buildings Can Be Designed to Withstand Earthquakes. Why Doesn’t the U.S. Build More of Them?” The New York Times, The New York Times, 4 June 2019, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/03/us/earthquake-preparedness-usa-japan.html">https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/03/us/earthquake-preparedness-usa-japan.htm</a>. </small></p>

<p><small>“Lists of 21st-Century Earthquakes.” Wikipedia, Wikimedia Foundation, 10 Mar. 2023, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_21st-century_earthquakes#cite_note-FOOTNOTEISC2022-6">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_21st-century_earthquakes#cite_note-FOOTNOTEISC2022-6</a>. </small></p>

<p><small>“Where Do Earthquakes Occur?” British Geological Survey, 9 Dec. 2021, <a href="https://www.bgs.ac.uk/discovering-geology/earth-hazards/earthquakes/where-do-earthquakes-occur/#:~:text=Over%2080%20per%20cent%20of,active%20zone%20in%20the%20world">https://www.bgs.ac.uk/discovering-geology/earth-hazards/earthquakes/where-do-earthquakes-occur</a>. </small></p>

<p><small>“Earthquake Magnitude Scale.” Michigan Technological University, Michigan Technological University, 4 Oct. 2021, <a href="https://www.mtu.edu/geo/community/seismology/learn/earthquake-measure/magnitude/">https://www.mtu.edu/geo/community/seismology/learn/earthquake-measure/magnitude/</a>.</small></p>

<p>Written by Eliška Levisohn</p>]]></content><author><name>Eliška Levisohn</name></author><category term="Earthquakes in Turkey/Environmental Issues" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Small earthquakes are quite common worldwide; a million or so happen each year. However, certain places are more susceptible to earthquakes due to their location near the seven major tectonic plates. As countries in those areas have continued to develop, new technologies lessen the damage and give citizens earthquake warnings, lowering mortality rates. So although high-magnitude earthquakes remain dangerous, the amount of damage they inflict is dependent on access to technologies to prevent earthquakes and governmental measures taken towards minimizing the dame of earthquakes. This is shown through the comparison of Japan and Haiti.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/History%20of%20Earthquakes%20around%20the%20world.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/History%20of%20Earthquakes%20around%20the%20world.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Impacts of Earthquakes in Turkey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impacts of Earthquakes in Turkey" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/-Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Impacts-of-Earthquakes-in-Turkey/"><![CDATA[<p>On February 6th, 2023, Turkey was hit by a powerful earthquake with a magnitude of 6.9. It struck the eastern province of Van, causing extensive damage to buildings and infrastructure and claiming the lives of at least 45,000 people. The impacts of the earthquake were widespread and impacted many civilians. Many residents were left homeless, without access to necessities such as food or clean water. The earthquake triggered landslides and rockfalls, making rescue efforts difficult and dangerous for first responders.</p>

<p>Despite those effects, one of the most devastating impacts of the earthquake was the high death toll. As rescue teams worked to search and uncover survivors from the fallen rubble, the death toll continued to hike up. The number of people affected was even worse than normal, because the earthquake hit in the early hours of the morning, catching many residents off guard and trapping them inside their homes. As a result, many people were unable to escape in time and were buried alive. In addition, the earthquake caused significant damage to infrastructure. Homes, schools, hospitals, and other buildings were destroyed or badly damaged. The earthquake also caused major disruptions to transportation, making it difficult for emergency responders to reach affected areas and for residents to access aid and resources.</p>

<p>The earthquake also had a significant economic impact on the region, with many businesses and industries affected by the destruction of infrastructure and the loss of lives. The region is known for its agriculture and livestock industries, both of which were severely impacted by the earthquake. The destruction of homes and buildings also led to a decline in tourism, which is a major source of income for the region. The World Bank’s Disaster Assessment Report estimates that the damage caused by the earthquake will total up to more than $34 billion dollars. The earthquake had a psychological impact on the residents of the affected areas. Many residents were traumatized by the experience and were left feeling vulnerable and uncertain about their future. The loss of loved ones and the destruction of homes and communities left residents struggling to cope with the aftermath of the earthquake.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of the earthquake, there have been calls for increased investment in disaster preparedness and management in Turkey and around the world. While it is impossible to predict or prevent natural disasters, taking proactive measures to prepare for them can help to minimize the loss of life and damage to infrastructure. This includes investing in early warning systems, training for emergency responders, and ensuring that critical infrastructure is designed and built to withstand the impacts of natural disasters. The loss and damage of the earthquake will forever serve as a reminder of the importance of disaster preparedness and management in reducing the impact of natural disasters. As we move towards the future, hopefully, the new preparations learned from this experience will improve our response towards future similarly devastating earthquakes and allow us to preserve more lives.</p>

<p><small> Sources: </small></p>

<p><small>Akgun, A. A., &amp; Vaněk, J. (2023, March 9). Earthquake in Turkey exposes gap between seismic knowledge and action – but it is possible to prepare. The Conversation. <a href="https://theconversation.com/earthquake-in-turkey-exposes-gap-between-seismic-knowledge-and-action-but-it-is-possible-to-prepare-199379">https://theconversation.com/earthquake-in-turkey-exposes-gap-between-seismic-knowledge-and-action-but-it-is-possible-to-prepare-199379</a> </small><br />
<small>“Earthquake Damage in Türkiye Estimated to Exceed $34 billion.” World Bank, 27 February 2023, <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2023/02/27/earthquake-damage-in-turkiye-estimated-to-exceed-34-billion-world-bank-disaster-assessment-report">https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2023/02/27/earthquake-damage-in-turkiye-estimated-to-exceed-34-billion-world-bank-disaster-assessment-report</a>. </small><br />
<small>Accessed 18 March 2023. Mime, M. (2023, March 6). The economic cost of Turkey’s earthquake could be as high as $15 billion. CNN. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/06/middleeast/turkey-earthquake-economic-cost-mime-intl/index.html">https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/06/middleeast/turkey-earthquake-economic-cost-mime-intl/index.html</a> </small><br />
<small>Turkey earthquake: More than 100 dead as 6.9-magnitude quake hits Van. (2023, February 6). BBC News. <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-64824516">https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-64824516</a> </small><br />
<small>U.S. Geological Survey. (n.d.). M6.9 - Eastern Turkey. Retrieved March 10, 2023, from <a href="https://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/map/?extent=-46.67959,-80.15625&amp;extent=63.39152,116.71875&amp;listOnlyShown=true">https://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/map/?extent=-46.67959,-80.15625&amp;extent=63.39152,116.71875&amp;listOnlyShown=true</a>
</small></p>

<p>Written by Sophia Huang</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Huang</name></author><category term="Earthquakes in Turkey/Environmental Issues" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On February 6th, 2023, Turkey was hit by a powerful earthquake with a magnitude of 6.9. It struck the eastern province of Van, causing extensive damage to buildings and infrastructure and claiming the lives of at least 45,000 people. The impacts of the earthquake were widespread and impacted many civilians. Many residents were left homeless, without access to necessities such as food or clean water. The earthquake triggered landslides and rockfalls, making rescue efforts difficult and dangerous for first responders.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Impacts%20of%20the%20Earthquakes%20in%20Turkey.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Impacts%20of%20the%20Earthquakes%20in%20Turkey.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>