<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-18T15:05:46-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ourgeneration Club</title><subtitle>This is homepage for SHS Ourgeneration Club.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is Abortion?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/What-is-abortion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Abortion?" /><published>2022-09-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/What-is-abortion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/What-is-abortion/">&lt;p&gt;Abortion. A widely controversial topic that has been hotly debated and discussed, especially in the past year with the overturning of Roe v. Wade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since ancient times, abortions have been performed through a number of methods. Common practices include herbal abortifacients, sharp tools, or traditional medicine that date back to ancient China, Egypt, India, and the Roman Empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With abortion’s extensive history in so many cultures, it is no surprise that laws were also put in place regarding this practice. At different points in time, Japan, China, India, and ancient Rome all had bans placed on abortions with varying levels of severity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why do people ban abortions? Religious followers vehemently quote from the Old Testament, which states that life starts at conception; thus, aborting a fetus would result in murder. Some medical scholars refer to the Hippocratic Oath, stating that it prevents them from performing abortions. Even today, anti-abortionists sport a wide range of reasons that only they can justify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this month’s issue, we address today’s most pressing issue regarding abortion: Roe v. Wade. You will get to read the two sides of this topic, as well as a timeline regarding the history of abortion, and eventually form your own educated opinion on the ethics of abortion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interactive content title: Abortion around the world: all on one line
	subtitle: for those visual thinkers…
first section title: some statistics for you…
24  countries prohibit abortion
41  allow abortion to save a woman’s life
48  allow abortion to preserve health
13  allow abortion on socioeconomic grounds
75  allow abortion on request (with gestational limits)
timeline section w/ some other info:
The following timeline illustrates abortion rights in the top 10 most populous countries throughout the 19th-21st centuries
countries included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;China  2. India  3. U.S.  4. Indonesia  5. Pakistan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nigeria  7. Brazil  8. Bangladesh  9. Russia  10. Mexico
actual timeline: 
melody somehow get it on there we can chop it up into a few rows
Interactive: Timeline
in conclusion…:
China
Abortion is accessible to all women, in public and private hospitals countrywide. There is not much debate surrounding the morality of it, as traditional Chinese beliefs perceive the right to live as starting at birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India
Abortion is legal for rape victims and in case of severe fetal anomaly, but it requires a long process of approval, resulting in it being inaccessible to many people.
U.S.
The legality of abortion depends on the states. As of now, many states are split between protecting abortion and making it illegal.
Indonesia
Abortion is legal in medical emergencies, as well as in cases of severe fetal anomaly. It’s also legal for cases of rape before six weeks of gestation have passed. The process is severely complicated and ambiguous, and many people are unable to obtain an abortion. For every 100,000 live births, there are 305 maternal deaths.
Pakistan
Policies are generally against abortion, except in ambiguous cases of “good faith” or “necessary treatment”. Many women attempt to get unsafe abortions, which majorly contributes to avoidable injuries and death. In 2002, 197,000 women were estimated to have been hospitalized for unsafe abortion complications.
Nigeria
Abortion laws in Nigeria have not changed since 1861. They remain illegal, unless done to save the life of a pregnant woman. Around 50.6 per 1,000 women of reproductive age attempt to get an abortion, making it one of the highest rates in the world.
Brazil
Many women attempt to buy Misoprostol on the black market in order to get an illegal abortion. Abortion is legal only to save a woman’s life, or if the pregnancy was a result of rape or incest. Unsafe abortions are the fourth leading cause of maternal deaths in the country.
Bangladesh
Abortion is only legal to save a woman’s life. However, Menstrual Regulation, which is used to bring back regular menstruation, is available. Many women are unaware of this, and gestational limits are unclear, which causes many people to be incorrectly denied when attempting to find Menstrual Regulation care.
Russia
Abortion is legal on request until the 12th week of pregnancy, and it is also available in later pregnancies under special circumstances.
Mexico
There are no national-level regulations on abortion. 8 out of 32 states, as well as Mexico City, are working on providing safe paths to abortion.
what can you do?:
You can visit https://reproductiverights.org/get-involved/ to learn more about abortion, and how you can act on it. If you live in the U.S., abortion will be an important topic of conflict in the upcoming 2022 midterm elections for the House of Representatives and the Senate. Encourage the adults around you to learn about the potential candidates and how to vote for them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melody Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Abortion. A widely controversial topic that has been hotly debated and discussed, especially in the past year with the overturning of Roe v. Wade.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/ourgeneration.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Justice: Landmark Supreme Court Decisions Then and Now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Social-Justice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Justice: Landmark Supreme Court Decisions Then and Now" /><published>2022-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Social-Justice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Social-Justice/">&lt;p&gt;The Reconstruction Era, a nationwide effort to rebuild and stabilize the country after the Civil War and assimilate freed slaves into society with their newly conferred rights, had officially ended in 1877, a little over a decade before. Yet, this new withdrawal of Northern troops and influence from the south led to the rise of what we know today to be the Era of Jim Crow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1890, the state of Louisiana passed the Separate Car Act, requiring all railroads to provide train cars that were “separate but [had] equal accommodations” which would segregate black passengers from whites. This was following a chain of similar bills in neighboring states, after Florida took the lead by passing the first law dictating that railroad cars must be segregated in 1887.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In resistance to the Separate Car Act, Homer Adolph Plessy pulled a “Rosa Parks.” Or rather, Rosa Parks was the one who pulled a “Plessy” several decades later. On June 7th, 1892, Plessy took a train, sat down on the car for whites, refused to leave, and was subsequently arrested. While being tried for violating the Separate Car Act, Plessy countered by claiming that the law was unconstitutional and it infringed on the 14th Amendment which guaranteed freed slaves citizenship, rights, and equal protection. (The judge presiding over his case was Hon. John Ferguson, hence the name, Plessy v. Ferguson.) Four years later, after a series of court battles, the case finally made it way up to the Supreme Court, where the court ruled in a landmark case that “separate but equal” was constitutional. They argued that the Equal Protection Clause in the 14th Amendment, which mandates that states cannot discriminate against individuals based on unrelated differences, does not apply to “social rights.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this case, the Supreme Court constitutionalized segregation, and it marked the rise of Jim Crow laws. The case was not overturned until 1954, with the Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka, which ruled that segregation in public schools was unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plessy v. Ferguson remains today as one of the most notable cases concerning social rights in American history. One of the conservative justices, Samuel Alito, who voted in favor of Roe v. Wade’s overturning, refers to Plessy v. Ferguson as an example of an “egregiously wrong” decision and compares it to Roe v. Wade, calling them both unconstitutional “from the day it was decided.” What he doesn’t seem to accept is that Plessy’s case legalized segregation and took away countless rights of blacks for decades, while Roe v. Wade protected women’s rights and its recent overturning in favor of fetal rights proves the opposite effect. These two landmark decisions both had lasting effects on American society and history. While Plessy forced an uphill battle for the rights of millions of black Americans in the 20th century, we can only wait to see whether or not Roe’s overturning will follow similar historical trends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melody Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">The Reconstruction Era, a nationwide effort to rebuild and stabilize the country after the Civil War and assimilate freed slaves into society with their newly conferred rights, had officially ended in 1877, a little over a decade before. Yet, this new withdrawal of Northern troops and influence from the south led to the rise of what we know today to be the Era of Jim Crow.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/ourgeneration.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Roe v. Wade: How was the Decision Made?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Roe-Wade-How-was-the-Decision-Made/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" Roe v. Wade: How was the Decision Made?" /><published>2022-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Roe-Wade-How-was-the-Decision-Made</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Roe-Wade-How-was-the-Decision-Made/">&lt;p&gt;Roe v. Wade was a legal decision made by the supreme court in 1973, striking down the Texas statute of criminalizing abortion. The decision made the statement that a woman’s right to abortion is part of the privacy that is protected in the 14th amendment. Before Roe v. Wade, states placed heavy restrictions on abortions, many of them illegalizing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1970, Norma McCorvey, a.k.a Jane Roe (to preserve privacy), took federal action against Henry Rade, who was the district attorney of Dallas county in Texas. The question was “Does the Constitution recognize a woman’s right to terminate her pregnancy by abortion?” Roe asserted that she had an absolute right to terminate her pregnancy at any time, but the Supreme Court disagreed, trying to balance a woman’s right of privacy as well as trying to regulate abortion. Finally, the Supreme Court decided to place a point in the pregnancy; after a certain amount of time, no more abortion would be allowed. They set this point at around 24 weeks of pregnancy, meaning that before 24 weeks, women were allowed to have abortions legally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been repeated challenges against Roe v. Wade from 1973 to before 2022, but none succeeded in overturning it, but managed to narrow the scope further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, June 24, 2022, the Supreme Court overturned Roe v. Wade, removing 50 years of legal protection for abortion rights. This left abortion laws and restrictions to the states. Because of laws that were put into place before the ruling, abortion is now outlawed in many states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, Idaho, Texas, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Wisconsin, Missouri, Arkansas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, Tennessee, Kentucky, Indiana, and West Virginia have banned abortion. Georgia has stated that any abortions after 6 weeks of pregnancy are illegal, while Utah, North Carolina, and Florida have stated that abortions after 20 weeks are illegal. In California, Washington, Oregon, Alaska, New Mexico, Minnesota, Illinois, New York, Vermont, Massachusetts, New Jersey, Connecticut, and Maine, abortions are completely legal. In Nevada, Colorado, Nebraska, Kansas, Virginia, Pennsylvania, New Hampshire, and Rhode Island, abortions are legal but limited. For Arizona, Utah, Wyoming, Montana, North Dakota, Iowa, Michigan, Ohio, and South Carolina, bans are being considered but are not in place yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melody Yu</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Roe v. Wade was a legal decision made by the supreme court in 1973, striking down the Texas statute of criminalizing abortion. The decision made the statement that a woman’s right to abortion is part of the privacy that is protected in the 14th amendment. Before Roe v. Wade, states placed heavy restrictions on abortions, many of them illegalizing them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/ourgeneration.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ourgeneration Club Official Website!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-generation-club/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to  Ourgeneration Club Official Website!" /><published>2022-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-generation-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-generation-club/">&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by! We’ll post articles, useful links, and new events for students going to SHS Our Generation Club!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melody Yu</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Thanks for stopping by! We’ll post articles, useful links, and new events for students going to SHS Our Generation Club!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/ourgeneration.jpeg" /></entry></feed>